<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><xml><records><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mcdowell, Timothy</author><author>Tupper, Kendra</author><author>Betz, Fred</author><author>Debaillie, Lee</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>SimBuild 2012 Conference Progam</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>0</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2012</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Program for SimBuild 2012</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zavala, Victor M.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>REAL-TIME RESOLUTION OF CONFLICTING OBJECTIVES IN BUILDING ENERGY</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>1-8</pages><keywords/><dates><year>1</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_1.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>We present an utopia-tracking multiobjective optimiza- tion strategy to resolve conflicting objectives in real-time energy management. Conflicts arise frequently from the need to balance economic and noneconomic metrics such as energy demand and occupant comfort. We demon- strate that the proposed approach leads to better perfor- mance compared with the traditional weighting approach. In particular, we demonstrate that improper adjustment of weights can lead to large excursions in performance. The proposed approach automatically locates the opti- mal weights and does not require the computation of the Pareto front, making it ideal for real-time implementation.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zhu, Jianmin</author><author>Shen, Ling</author><author>Yin, Rongxin</author><author>Lu, Yan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A TWO-STAGE SIMULATION-BASED ON-LINE OPTIMIZATION SCHEME FOR HVAC DEMAND RESPONSE</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>9-16</pages><keywords/><dates><year>9</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_9.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.ibpsa.us/simbuild2012/Papers/SB12_TS01a_2_Zhu.pdf</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The on-line control optimization for building heating, ventilation and air conditioning (HVAC) systems is crucial for automatic demand response. Simulation- based optimization techniques usually require intensive computation, even with advanced optimization algorithms, and therefore are not feasible for on-line decision making. This article presents a two-stage scheme in which an “optimal strategy pool” is generated by off-line optimization on the identified weather patterns. And only a small number of strategies are subject to on-line simulation evaluation. This two- stage approach shows superior capability of identifying optimal DR strategies and reducing on-line computation load, simultaneously. A case study with EnergyPlus simulation of a large education facility at Berkeley, CA is included.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Asadi, Ehsan</author><author>Silva, Manuel Gameiro da</author><author>Antunes, Carlos Henggeler</author><author>Dias, Luís</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>MULTI-OBJECTIVE OPTIMIZATION MODEL FOR BUILDING RETROFIT STRATEGIES</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>17-24</pages><keywords/><dates><year>17</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_17.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>In face of the multiple choices for retrofitting a building, the main issue is to identify those that prove to be the most effective in the long term. In this work, a simulation-based multi-objective optimization scheme (a combination of TRNSYS, GenOpt and a Tchebycheff optimization technique developed in MATLAB) is employed to minimize energy use in the building in a cost effective manner, while considering the occupant’s requirements. In order to achieve the best compromise solutions a wide decision space is considered, including alternative materials for external wall insulation, roof insulation, different window types, and installation of solar collector in the existing building. An existing house needing retrofit is taken as a case study and the effectiveness of the approach is demonstrated for identifying a number of Pareto optimal solutions for building retrofit. The results verify the practicability of the approach and highlight potential problems that may arise.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Pekdemir, Emir Aykut</author><author>Muehleisen, Ralph T.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A PARAMETRIC STUDY OF THE THERMAL PERFORMANCE OF DOUBLE SKIN FAÇADES AT DIFFERENT CLIMATES USING ANNUAL ENERGY SIMULATION</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>211-218</pages><keywords/><dates><year>21</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.ijrobp.2008.07.056</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_21.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This research analyzes the thermal performance of several types of Double Skin Façades [DSF] to determine which are best suited for each climate zone. The purpose of the research is to help guide project owners and unspecialized architects during their decision making process, when they choose to design a DSF. Using Building Energy Modeling [BEM] software, various types of naturally ventilated DSFs are analyzed in all seventeen ASHRAE climate zones. The thermal performance of the DSF is determined by comparing the building energy use data of a generic office building. The different types of DSFs are created following a set of parameters such as stratification type, permissibility of airflow, and width of interstitial space.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Basarkar, Mangesh</author><author>Donnell, James O.</author><author>Haves, Philip</author><author>Settlemyre, Kevin</author><author>Maile, Tobias</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>MAPPING HVAC SYSTEMS FOR SIMULATION IN ENERGYPLUS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>25-31</pages><issue>July</issue><keywords/><dates><year>25</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_25.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>For building energy simulation tools to be accessible to designers, tool interfaces should present a conventional view of HVAC systems to the user, and then map this view to the internal data model used in the tool. The paper outlines a process that enables design engineers to create HVAC system representations using industry standard terminology and system, icon and typological representations and convert that unified representation into the format required by the whole building energy simulation tool EnergyPlus. This paper describes each stage of the conversion process, which involves transformations between the following representations: 1) engineer’s representation, 2) component connectivity representation, 3) representation in the internal data model used in the Simergy graphical user interface for EnergyPlus, and 4) EnergyPlus representation. The paper also describes mappings between these representations and the development of a rule-based validation and assignment framework required to implement that mapping. In addition, the paper describes the implementation of this process in Simergy.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Malhotra, Mini</author><author>Im, Piljae</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>DEVELOPMENT OF A FLEXIBLE , MULTIZONE , MULTIFAMILY BUILDING SIMULATION MODEL</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>32-39</pages><keywords/><dates><year>32</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_32.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>As weatherization of multifamily buildings becomes more widespread, improvement is needed in energy audit tools for multifamily buildings. On the wish list of field experts is the capability to model multizone build- ings (i.e., one thermal zone per dwelling unit) with simplified user input to improve analysis of decentral- ized and centralized HVAC and domestic hot water systems without creating detailed building models. To provide the desired capabilities, development of an enhanced energy audit tool was begun in 2011. The tool is a strategically structured, flexible, one-zone-per-unit DOE-2.1e model coupled with a simplified user inter- face to model small to large multifamily buildings with decentralized or centralized systems and associated energy measures. This paper describes the modeling concept and its implementation.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Georgescu, Michael</author><author>Eisenhower, Bryan</author><author>Mezi, Igor</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>CREATING ZONING APPROXIMATIONS TO BUILDING ENERGY MODELS USING THE KOOPMAN OPERATOR</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>40-47</pages><keywords/><dates><year>40</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_40.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>As the scope of building construction increases and de- signs become more integrated, building energy models have found widespread use in evaluating building per- formance. Despite the growing sophistication of build- ing modelling tools, errors can arise from the approxima- tions that are made during model creation. This paper ad- dresses model zoning, i.e., how the volume of a building is divided into regions where properties are assumed to be uniform. Zoning is important during the creation of a model because the accuracy of prediction from simu- lating a model reduces when dissimilar zones are lumped together. In this paper, a systematic approach to creat- ing zoning approximations is introduced to investigate the effect of zoning on simulation accuracy. Applying the Koopman operator, an infinite-dimensional, linear oper- ator that captures nonlinear, finite-dimensional dynamics without linearization, a detailed building model is stud- ied. Using the Koopman operator, the temperature history of rooms produced by a building simulation can be de- composed into Koopman modes. These modes identify dynamically significant behavior which will form a basis for the creation of zoning approximations. An implemen- tation of this technique is illustrated in a building model of an actual building designed with both mechanical and natural conditioning.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Yazdanshenas, Eshagh</author><author>Marston, Annie</author><author>Baumann, Oliver</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>AN INVESTIGATION TO OPTIMIZE THE MECHANICAL SYSTEMS TO MEET COMFORT CRITERIA IN A LARGE ATRIUM</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>48-55</pages><keywords/><dates><year>48</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_48.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>A large office building has a 140 m atrium which is split into four sections: atriums 1, 2, and 3 and a “sky garden” which is the upper most atrium with trees and shrubs. The atrium was simulated first in EnergyPlus to obtain the correct surface conditions for the critical days and then in Star CCM+. The first CFD analysis showed uncomfortable temperatures on the upper balconies in each section in the summer months. The optimization of the jet nozzles angles, the additional components and the supply temperature adjustment has shown a promising improvement in the thermal comfort on the balconies.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Urban, Bryan</author><author>Elliott, Diana</author><author>Sachs, Olga</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>TOWARDS BETTER MODELING OF RESIDENTIAL THERMOSTATS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>56-62</pages><keywords/><dates><year>56</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_56.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Thermostats are notorious for being difficult to use. Consequently, heating is manually controlled by occupants in most homes, including those with programmable thermostats. Conventional modeling approaches fail at capturing behavioral elements by relying on fixed setpoint schedules. To accurately assess the energy impact of thermostat operation requires two changes to the way simulations are carried out. First, thermostat setpoint programs must be defined based on how thermostats are actually operated instead of the usually assumed ideal behavior; and second, realistic occupancy schedules must be adopted instead of average schedules. This may require layering of behavioral logic atop thermostat logic. In this paper we present an approach for doing this using Energy Plus and American Time Use Survey (ATUS) data, together with some examples.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Dutton, Spencer</author><author>Zhang, Hui</author><author>Zhai, Yongchao</author><author>Arens, Ed</author><author>Smires, Youness Bennani</author><author>Brunswick, Sam</author><author>Konis, Kyle</author><author>Haves, Phil</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>APPLICATION OF A STOCHASTIC WINDOW USE MODEL IN ENERGYPLUS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>63-70</pages><keywords/><dates><year>63</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_63.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.ibpsa.us/simbuild2012/Papers/SB12_TS01c_3_Dutton.pdf</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Natural ventilation, used appropriately, has the potential to provide both significant HVAC energy savings, and improvements in occupant satisfaction. Central to the development of natural ventilation models is the need to accurately represent the behavior of building occupants. The work covered in this paper describes a method of implementing a stochastic window model in EnergyPlus. Simulated window use data from three stochastic window opening models was then compared to measured window opening behavior, collected in a naturally-ventilated office in California. Recommendations regarding the selection of stochastic window use models, and their implementation in EnergyPlus, are presented.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bhandari, Mahabir</author><author>Srinivasan, Ravi</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>WINDOW-WALL INTERFACE CORRECTION FACTORS: THERMAL MODELING OF INTEGRATED FENESTRATION AND OPAQUE ENVELOPE SYSTEMS FOR IMPROVED PREDICTION OF ENERGY USE</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>71-74</pages><keywords/><dates><year>71</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_71.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The boundary conditions for thermal modeling of fenestration systems assume an adiabatic condition between the fenestration system installed and the opaque envelope system. This theoretical adiabatic boundary condition may not be appropriate owing to heat transfer at the interfaces, particularly for aluminum-framed windows affixed to metal-framed walls. In such scenarios, the heat transfer at the interface may increase the discrepancy between real world thermal indices and laboratory measured or calculated indices based on NFRC Rating System.This paper discusses the development of Window-Wall Interface (WWI) Correction Factors to improve energy impacts of building envelope systems.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Maing, Minjung</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>VIRTUAL MOCK-UP MODELING AS STUDY MODEL OF BUILDING ENVELOPE PERFORMANCE AND DESIGN</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>75-82</pages><keywords/><dates><year>75</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_75.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The current use of mock-ups in building envelope design is to serve as critical milestones in validating the envelope performance. There is increasing emphasis of the importance of physical mock-ups, in particular during pre-construction stages, in emerging guidelines, specifications and building practice methods. However physical mock-ups construe the design process as linear and can exacerbrate the project workflow when problems are discovered through these mock-ups at this late building design phase. To allow for more flexibility and interaction of the mock-up validation process into the re-terative design generation process, an alternate more robust mode of investigation needs to be explored. Virtual mock-ups are economical, less time consuming and robust options to their physical counterpart including their potential to integrate with building information modeling. This paper discusses research conducted on implications of virtual mock-ups and how their implementation, through case studies, was used as study models within an integrated exchange platform.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cianfrone, Christian; Neil Norris; Patrick Roppel; Medgar Marceau</author><author>Norris, Neil</author><author>Roppel, Patrick</author><author>Marceau, Medgar</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>THERMAL PERFORMANCE OF THREE?DIMENSIONAL BUILDING ENVELOPE ASSEMBLIES AND DETAILS FOR IMPROVING THE ACCURACY OF WHOLE BUILDING PERFORMANCE SIMULATION</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>83-95</pages><keywords><keyword>filtrado</keyword><keyword>final</keyword></keywords><dates><year>83</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_83.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Thermal bridging through insulation layers in the building envelope reduces the thermal performance of building envelope assemblies and heat flow through thermal bridging can have a detrimental impact on wholebuilding energy performance. So, it is important for energy modelers, building engineers, and architects to consider the effects of thermal bridging when evaluating the expected performance of building envelope details and when designing building envelopes for energy efficient buildings. However, it is difficult to determine how much heat flows through thermal bridges using typical approaches, such as the areaweighted average of Uvalues, especially when dealing with threedimensional (3D) heat flow paths. In ASHRAE Research Project 1365 (RP1365), a methodology was developed, using a calibrated 3D model, that enables designers to account for heat flow through thermal bridges in a simple and practical manner. This approach can improve the accuracy of whole building performance simulations where complex thermal bridging is often ignored. This paper will provide an overview of RP1365 and its potential impact on energy simulation. The impact on whole building energy performance will be examined for three building types in four different climates</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Attia, Shady</author><author>Wanas, Omar</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>THE DATABASE OF EGYPTIAN BUILDING ENVELOPES (DEBE): A DATABASE FOR BUILDING ENERGY SIMULATIONS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>96-103</pages><keywords/><dates><year>96</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_96.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper is a part of an ongoing research that aims to describe the influence of building constructions on energy consumption through a survey that is conducted in Cairo and its surrounding residential neighbourhoods. An inventory of the selected neighbourhoods envelope constructions and their characteristics is described in accordance with the new Egyptian energy standard for residential buildings. After thorough screening and classification, the constructions are digitalized and uploaded in an online open source database where constructions properties are listed, made available in .idf and .ddb formats (EnergyPlus and DesignBuilder respectively) and illustrated graphically. This Database of Egyptian Building Envelopes (DEBE) facilitates the input modelling of constructions and enables users to explore standard complying alternative constructions.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Garay, Raymond Sterling</author><author>Costa, Andrea</author><author>Messervey, Thomas</author><author>Mastrodonato, Christian</author><author>Keane, Marcus M.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>SWIMMING POOL HALL HVAC MODELLING, SIMULATION AND END OF SETBACK NEURAL NETWORK PREDICTION: A DETAILED CASE STUDY</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>104-111</pages><keywords><keyword>Artificial Neural Networks</keyword><keyword>Building Modelling and Simulation</keyword><keyword>Reduced Order HVAC Systems</keyword><keyword>Swimming Pool Modelling and Simulation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>104</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_104.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.ibpsa.us/simbuild2012/Papers/SB12_TS02b_1_Garay.pdf\nhttp://www.ibpsa.org/?page_id=156</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This paper presents a novel methodology for applying modelling and simulation techniques to a swimming pool environment aimed at achieving energy savings by optimising the end of setback (EoS) schedule of the heating, ventilation and air conditioning (HVAC) system. The Building Controls Virtual Test-Bed (BCVTB) simulation platform is used to integrate different modelling and simulation tools to improve the accuracy of the simulations while reducing modelling effort. To test the feasibility of using artificial intelligence techniques in optimising the EoS, an application using artificial neural networks (ANN) is developed and discussed. A detailed case study is also presented and discussed.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Eisenhower, Bryan</author><author>Gasljevic, Kazimir</author><author>Mezi, Igor</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>CONTROL-ORIENTED DYNAMIC MODELING AND CALIBRATION OF A CAMPUS THEATER USING MODELICA</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>112-119</pages><keywords/><dates><year>112</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_112.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>In order to design and assess the dynamic performance of building automation systems, accurate control-oriented models are needed. Previous modeling languages do not accurately capture transients and state information to the fidelity that is needed for rigorous control-theoretic analy- sis. With the recent progress in building energy modeling in Modelica, these transients, and the dynamics of the sys- tem in general, can are captured more accurately. In this paper we will discuss necessary methodologies that are needed to construct and calibrate an energy model for the purpose of control system design and tuning. We will dis- cuss topics pertaining to this process including selection of appropriate steady state and dynamic data for model tuning. A case study will be included which investigates the dynamic performance of a building containing a movie theater and acoustic sound stage. Frequency domain con- trol analysis will be presented using the calibrated model</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Munshi, Madhav</author><author>Tuhus-Dubrow, Dan</author><author>An, John</author><author>Coffey, Brian</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>PRACTICAL TECHNIQUES FOR AUTOMATED CALIBRATION OF EXISTING MODELS FOR USE IN BUILDING OPERATIONS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>120-127</pages><keywords/><dates><year>120</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_120.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Building energy models constructed during the design phase can be used during building operations for benchmarking, fault detection and diagnosis, controls optimization and retrofit analysis. For most such applications, the model must be calibrated to at least roughly match measured data. This calibration process can be effectively framed and solved as an error minimization problem by calibration parameters and bounds. Although the final determination of parameter values is algorithmically, there is judgment necessary to set up and solve the problem. This paper demonstrates some practical techniques for setting up and solving the problem with GenOpt, including the iterative process of solving for successively more complete problem statements. Additionally, the paper discusses some of the ways in which modeling expertise plays an important illustrated by reference to recent projects. role, illustrated by reference to recent projects.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Singh, Sukreet</author><author>Martinez, Andrea</author><author>Kensek, Karen</author><author>Schiler, Marc</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>COMPARISON OF TWO DIFFERENT SIMULATION PROGRAMS WHILE CALIBRATING THE SAME BUILDING</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>128-135</pages><keywords/><dates><year>128</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_128.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>An existing institutional building of 95,287 square feet was calibrated for energy usage using Design Builder and eQuest. The whole building simulation models were made based on precise building geometry, occupancy, and equipment power and lighting densities. Building schedules were input to more closely relate the digital model to the actual building’s use (occupancy, heating, cooling, lighting, and ventilation), and some on-site measurements of plug loads were taken. Load balance, sizing of systems, electrical and gas consumption, and end uses of fuel consumption are compared. This paper explores the differences between the outputs and workability of both simulation tools. process, the main differences in modeling and simulating in the two software programs were observed and documented.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Blervaque, Hubert</author><author>Stabat, Pascal</author><author>Filfli, Sila</author><author>Muresan, Cristian</author><author>Marchio, Dominique</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>COMPARATIVE ANALYSIS OF AIR-TO-AIR HEAT PUMP MODELS FOR BUILDING ENERGY SIMULATION Hubert</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>136-143</pages><keywords><keyword>Low energy building</keyword><keyword>building system performance simulation</keyword><keyword>dynamic simulation rules</keyword><keyword>air-to-air heat pump</keyword><keyword>Modelica</keyword></keywords><dates><year>136</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_136.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The decrease of heat demands in the low energy build- ings requires to reexamine modeling approaches in the building simulation, particularly the dynamic response of the building and its equipments lead to re-examine modeling rules. From a review of air-to-air heat pump models, three types are compared in order to evaluate the ability of each one to predict the energy consumption and power demands. These air-to-air heat pump models coupled to a single zone building are simulated on Modelica. The aim is to underline the advantages and the drawbacks of the different modeling approaches for dynamic simulation in respect of the different phenomena to represent.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Pertzborn, A. J.</author><author>Nellis, G. F.</author><author>Klein, S. A.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>AN EVALUATION OF THE EFFECTIVENESS OF PRE-COOLING IN A HYBRID GROUND SOURCE HEAT PUMP</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>144-151</pages><keywords/><dates><year>144</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_144.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Hybrid ground source heat pump (HyGSHP) systems for building heating and cooling are gaining popularity as a means of decreasing long term energy and maintenance costs while maintaining manageable first costs. In these systems there is a potential to use the ground not only as an immediate heat source or sink, but as an energy store. On a scale of hours, the ground store could be cooled by a hybrid component, such as a cooling tower, during the night in order to improve the heat rejection efficiency in cooling during the following day. This paper presents the results of a study of the ground as a thermal energy store on a short term basis.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Marsicek, Greg</author><author>Klein, Sanford</author><author>Greg Nellis</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>FEASIBILITY OF COMBINED SOLAR/HEAT PUMP SYSTEMS FOR REDUCED RESIDENTIAL CONDITIONING ENERGY CONSUMPTION</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>152-159</pages><keywords/><dates><year>152</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_152.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper investigates the impact of using an air- source heat pump system in a thermally efficient house for two locations: Chicago, IL and Dallas, TX. In addition to an air-source heat pump, a geothermal heat pump system is implemented in the Chicago location. The source energy savings over a conventional system is reported as well as the life cycle costs for each of these cases. The conventional system is a natural gas furnace and air conditioner. In addition, to improve the performance of the air-source heat pump system, photovoltaics and solar thermal systems are implemented to analyze the effects on the energy savings and life cycle costs.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, Liping</author><author>Haves, Philip</author><author>Breshears, John</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>THE ENERGY SAVING POTENTIAL OF MEMBRANE-BASED ENTHALPY RECOVERY IN VAV SYSTEMS FOR COMMERCIAL OFFICE BUILDINGS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>160-167</pages><keywords/><dates><year>160</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_160.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>A design tool to evaluate the heat and mass transfer effectiveness and pressure drop of a membrane-based enthalpy exchanger was developed and then used to optimize the configuration of an enthalpy exchanger for minimum pressure drop and maximum heat recovery effectiveness. Simulation was used in a parametric study to investigate the energy saving potential of the enthalpy recovery system. The case without energy recovery and air side economizer was used as a baseline. Two comparison cases for the implementation of enthalpy recovery with and without air side economizer were simulated in EnergyPlus. A case using a desiccant wheel for energy recovery was also investigated for comparison purposes. The simulation results show significant energy saving benefits from applying a low pressure drop, high effectiveness enthalpy exchanger in two US cities representing a range of humid climates. The sensitivity of the energy savings potential to pressure drop and heat and mass transfer effectivenesses is also presented.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Moore, Timothy C .</author><author>Ouzts, Peter J .</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>ZONAL APPROACH TO MODELING THERMALLY STRATIFIED ATRIA</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>168-176</pages><keywords/><dates><year>168</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_168.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Thermally stratified atria and similar spaces present challenges for building thermal-comfort and energy modeling. This work tests a zonal modeling method for dynamic thermal and energy simulation of a heavily glazed and thermally stratified atrium cooled by displacement ventilation. The goal of the study was to explore the extent to which this method offers any improvement over simpler methods with respect to assessing thermal comfort and energy consumption. This paper describes a thermal and bulk-airflow zonal modeling strategy that appears to capture the some of the principal effects of thermal plumes generated when glazed façades and other interior surfaces are heated by solar radiation. This approach may be applicable to a relatively broad range of projects with similar characte- ristics. A CFD tool running the same model of the space, but without the zonal subdivisions, was used to tune the dynamic thermal/bulk-airflow model and to assess the degree to which the latter provides consis- tently appropriate results with variation in solar gain. The zonal approach appears to have some advantage with respect to predicting thermal comfort as a function of heat removed from the interior of glazed façades; however, a comparison with a simpler method that does not use bulk-airflow modeling suggests that this simpler method may provide much of the same benefit with respect to assessing energy consumption.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Degraw, Jason W</author><author>Bahnfleth, William P</author><author>Musser, Amy</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>STREAMLINED MULTIZONE MODEL CREATION</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>177-184</pages><keywords/><dates><year>177</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_177.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Multizone modeling for the simulation of airflow and contaminant transport in buildings is intermediate in resolution and complexity between the extremes represented by single-zone models and computational fluid dynamics. The model input time requirements for a multizone building model are likely less than that required for the construction of computational fluid dynamics model of a building subset, but are likely more than required for a single-zone building model. This paper describes techniques intended to reduce the time required to construct a multizone representation of a building and presents data demonstrating their effectiveness. The airflow network that models the movement of air is constructed semi-automatically from input geometrical information, simple mechanical systems descriptions, and high-level weather parameters. The time required for model construction with this streamlined input procedure is measured using an implementation of the streamlined procedures. Model creation time is found to be approximately one quarter of the time required to construct the same model using standard techniques. When calibrated, the resulting models are sufficiently representative of the buildings under study to be useful for analytical and design studies.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Emmeric, Steven J.</author><author>Dols, W. Stuart</author><author>Polidoro, Brian</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>APPLICATION OF A NATURAL VENTILATION SYSTEM DESIGN TOOL TO A SCHOOL BUILDING</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>185-192</pages><keywords/><dates><year>185</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_185.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>A software tool (LoopDA) to aid in the design of natural ventilation systems has recently been udpated. This update implements a general method for sizing of natural ventilation system components, which allows direct consideration of stack and wind-driven airflow. The tool assists the designer in performing the following steps in developing the natural ventilation system design: establishing the global geometry and topology of zones and interconnecting flow paths, establishing design conditions, setting up and solving the representative loop equations based on the “design” form of the airflow components, and analyzing operation under a variety of conditions. This paper describes the updated tool and provides an example of its application to the design of a naturally ventilated school building.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bitsuamlak, Girma</author><author>Rasouli, Ashkan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>WIND-DRIVEN NATURAL VENTILATION IN A LOW-RISE BUILDING: A NUMERICAL AND EXPERIMENTAL STUDY</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>193-200</pages><keywords/><dates><year>193</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_193.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.researchgate.net/publication/278329498</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This paper presents a Boundary-Layer Wind Tunnel (BLWT) and numerical study on wind-driven natural ventilation for a low-rise building with multi-room partitioning, variable porosity size openings (in doors, windows and soffits), and a uniformly-distributed background leakage at a model-testing scale of 1:20. For the size of the building and openings considered, the experimental analyses indicated that the internal pressure due to cross-ventilation was 1.5 to 2.5 times higher when the ratio Ainlet/Aoutlet &gt;1 compared to Ainlet/Aoutlet &lt;1 . Room partitioning significantly affected the distribution of internal pressures, and hence the pressure drop, in the particular case considered the room partitioning enhanced the ventilation by breaking the large circulation zones that would have been produced for a single zone. The inlet discharge coefficients obtained in this experiment ranged from 0.65 to 1.08, similar to the results of various early studies. The numerical study further clarified the characteristics of the cross-ventilation with and without room partitioning.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Love, Andrea</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>ASSESSING THERMAL BRIDGES IN COMMERCIAL WALL SYSTEMS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>201-210</pages><keywords/><dates><year>201</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_201.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper focuses on the methodology developed utilizing the 2-D heat transfer program THERM to more accurately assess the 3-D heat flow from discontinuous bridging elements. Additionally, the research looks at a number of common connection, and compares the calculated U-values to simulation predictions and installed performance using thermal imaging. The paper will focus on both the methodology used, as well as the finding of the research to better comprehend the deviation in thermal performance between design intentions, simulation, and actual performance.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Delcroix, Benoit</author><author>Kummert, Michaël</author><author>Daoud, Ahmed</author><author>Hiller, Marion D.E.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>CONDUCTION TRANSFER FUNCTIONS IN TRNSYS MULTIZONE BUILDING MODEL: CURRENT IMPLEMENTATION, LIMITATIONS AND POSSIBLE IMPROVEMENTS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>219-226</pages><keywords/><dates><year>219</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_219.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The Conduction Transfer Function (CTF) method is used by many building energy performance simulation programs to calculate 1-D transient heat conduction through multi-layer envelope components. TRNSYS is one of these programs, and several authors have reported problems with the current CTF implementation in its multizone building model, known as Type 56. Reported problems are related to heavy and highly insulated slabs and short time-step simulations (less than 15-minute time-step). This paper documents the current implementation of CTF in Type 56. It then reports on our investigation of some issues with the current implementation and their causes. Workarounds and short-term solutions are assessed and longer-term improvements are discussed.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Soltaniehha, Mahdokht</author><author>Gardzelewski, Jon A.</author><author>Tan, Gang</author><author>Denzer, Anthony</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>PASSIVHAUS AND NET ZERO ENERGY RESIDENTIAL DESIGNS IN A COLD CLIMATE: A SIMULATION BASED DESIGN PROCESS FOR THE NEXT GENERATION OF GREEN HOMES</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>227-235</pages><keywords/><dates><year>227</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_227.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Today’s residential construction industry is capable of producing exceptionally high performing houses that far exceed compliance with local building codes. We feel that setting a target of Net-Zero Energy (NZE) is feasible in the US considering the design and construction technology available. This paper is part of an extensive project focusing on residential construction utilizing Passivhaus strategies with an emphasis on solar design and a target of Net- Zero energy use. The focus of this paper is on the role of simulation as a design aid in developing guidelines relating to building form, orientation, glazing, and roof area for solar electrical and thermal systems.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bueno, Bruno</author><author>Norford, Leslie</author><author>Hidalgo, Julia</author><author>Pigeon, Gregiore</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>PREDICTION OF THE URBAN HEAT ISLAND EFFECT TO BE USED IN BUILDING ENERGY ANALYSES</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>236-245</pages><keywords/><dates><year>236</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_236.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The increase in air temperature produced by urban- ization, a phenomenon known as the Urban Heat Island (UHI) effect, is often neglected in current building energy simulation practices. The UHI effect can have an impact on the energy consumption of buildings, especially those with low internal heat gains or with an inherent close interaction with the outdoor environment (e.g. naturally-ventilated buildings). This paper presents an Urban Weather Generator (UWG) to calculate air temperatures inside urban canyons from measurements at an operational weather station located in an open area outside a city. The model is evaluated against field data from Basel (Switzerland) and Toulouse (France). The expected error of UWG predictions is about 1 K, which stays within the range of air temperature variability observed in different locations of the same urban area.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Huang, Jianxiang</author><author>Guillermo, Jose</author><author>Laurent, Cedeño</author><author>Spengler, John</author><author>Reinhart, Christoph</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A GIS-BASED ASSESSMENT METHOD FOR MEAN RADIANT TEMPERATURE IN DENSE URBAN AREAS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>246-254</pages><keywords/><dates><year>246</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_246.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The mean radiant temperature (Tmrt) is among the most important factors affecting thermal comfort. Its assessment in dense cities has been complicated due to the presence of buildings, pavings, and infrastructure. This paper introduced the RAMUM model, a GIS based software method developed to simulate outdoor mean radiant temperature at micro- scale. The advantages of this method lie in its efficiency and resolution that supports the design of buildings, streets, and public open spaces. The model is evaluated using field measurements under cold and warm weather in Boston. This study is sponsored by the EFRI-1038264 award from the National Science Foundation (NSF), Division of Emerging Frontiers in Research and Innovation (EFRI).</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Rakha, Terek</author><author>Reinhart, Christoph</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>GENERATIVE URBAN MODELING: A DESIGN WORK FLOW FOR WALKABILITY-OPTIMIZED CITIES</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>255-262</pages><keywords/><dates><year>255</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_255.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper presents an urban analysis work flow using a Rhinoceros/Grasshopper massing tool. The tool utilizes terrain elevation models as part of the design process to subdivide sites and generate urban form to be explored parametrically. It can then be linked to various performance assessment methods. As a proof of concept, the study uses a walkability calculator for three urban form alternatives, and applies genetic algorithms to optimize generated designs through allocation of land-use. Results show a great diversity that converges to near optimal solutions. A discussion is drawn about the effort and time spent to model such iterations versus it’s automation using this work flow, and conclusions show the potentials, limitations and directions for future research work.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Schumann, Lars</author><author>Greenberg, Donald P .</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>ENVIRONMENT MAPPING FOR FAST AND ROBUST CALCULATION OF INDIRECT RADIANT ENERGY</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>263-269</pages><keywords/><dates><year>263</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_263.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Inclusion of site data, such as the surrounding structures, terrain, and vegetation, all of which modulate the amount of indirect radiation exchange between a building and its environment is necessary for accurate building energy simulation. While the impact of indirect radiant energy is potentially large, it is also very time consuming to calculate. Thus building energy simulations tend to incorporate simplified environment models or to omit the indirect radiation calculation altogether. This paper describes how a computer graphics algorithm, environment mapping, can be used to accurately calculate the indirect reflected radiant energy from the environment. We encode the complete panoramic environment surrounding a surface as an image texture that serves as a look-up table parameterized by direction. Different pieces of information such as sky, clouds, and buildings or obstructions are stored in separate textures that can be quickly overlaid. The method is fast, accurate, robust, and scalable.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>New, Joshua R.</author><author>Sanyal, Jibonananda</author><author>Bhandari, Mahabir</author><author>Shrestha, Som</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>AUTOTUNE E+ BUILDING ENERGY MODELS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>270-278</pages><keywords/><dates><year>270</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_270.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.ibpsa.us/simbuild2012/Papers/SB12_TS05a_1_New.pdf</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This paper introduces a novel “Autotune” methodol- ogy under development for calibrating building energy models (BEM). It is aimed at developing an automated BEM tuning methodology that enables models to reproduce measured data such as utility bills, sub-meter, and/or sensor data accurately and robustly by selecting best- match E+ input parameters in a systematic, automated, and repeatable fashion. The approach is applicable to a building retrofit scenario and aims to quantify the trade- offs between tuning accuracy and the minimal amount of “ground truth” data required to calibrate the model. Au- totune will use a suite of machine-learning algorithms de- veloped and run on supercomputers to generate calibra- tion functions. Specifically, the project will begin with a de-tuned model and then perform Monte Carlo simula- tions on the model by perturbing the “uncertain” parame- ters within permitted ranges. Machine learning algorithms will then extract minimal perturbation combinations that result in modeled results that most closely track sensor data. A large database of parametric EnergyPlus (E+) simulations has been made publicly available. Autotune is currently being applied to a heavily instrumented residen- tial building as well as three light commercial buildings in which a “de-tuned” model is autotuned using faux sensor data from the corresponding target E+ model.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Parekh, Anil</author><author>Kirney, Chris</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>THERMAL AND MECHANICAL SYSTEMS DESCRIPTORS FOR SIMPLIFIED ENERGY USE EVALUATION OF CANADIAN HOUSES</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>279-286</pages><keywords/><dates><year>279</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_279.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>For a quick and reliable energy evaluation of houses, one needs simple energy analysis software. A key requirement for simplified inputs is to have default data for house geometry, thermal and equipment characteristics based on vintage, type and region in which the house is located. Using data collected from more than 634,000 homes, statistical representative archetype data sets were developed for 35 climates zones and eight vintage periods. Representative numerical approaches were applied to develop archetype house characteristics. These data libraries are integrated with energy simulation software to assist in defining required defaults for geometry, building envelope and equipment. These defaults then provide guidance for a energy advisor to check against actual house data. Comparative energy analyses showed that the archetype characteristics are useful in quick field surveys.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Dybskiy, Pavel</author><author>Richman, Russell</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>AN INTERACTIVE WORKBENCH FOR MONITORING , IDENTIFICATION AND CALIBRATION OF BUILDING ENERGY MODELS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>287-294</pages><keywords/><dates><year>287</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_287.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper presents a concept and main capabilities of the Matlab-based Building Energy Modeling (BEM) Workbench developed at Ryerson University (Toronto, Canada). The workbench was designed as an interactive tool intended to facilitate and to provide common media for data processing tasks related to various building energy modeling procedures such as (i) on-site data monitoring, (ii) preparation of input data and analysis of simulation results, (iii) validation, verification and calibration of building energy models and (iv) estimation of building thermal parameters. To illustrate the use of the BEM-Workbench several working scenarios are presented. Known inputs from literature methodologies of building thermal parameter estimation were implemented into the workbench to demonstrate one of its purposes as a hypothesis testing tool. Another scenario was introduced to show how the workbench can be used to analyze a buildings model’s dynamic behavior, a critical step in the model’s calibration procedure. Programmatically, the workbench is configured as a set of Matlab GUI components and functions with capability to further expand its functionality.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>An, Lianjun</author><author>Horesh, Raya</author><author>Chae, Young T .</author><author>Lee, Young M.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>ESTIMATION OF THERMAL PARAMETERS OF BUILDINGS THROUGH INVERSE MODELING AND CLUSTERING FOR A PORTFOLIO OF BUILDINGS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>295-305</pages><keywords/><dates><year>295</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_295.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Estimating heat transfer parameters of building enve- lope for existing buildings is challenging due to limited data from sensors and meters. In this study, we have de- veloped a method for estimating heat transfer parameters of building envelope through clustering technique with in- verse modeling for portfolio of buildings. Firstly, we de- rived a static heat transfer model from a system of dy- namic equations by integrating the equations for differ- ent time periods. The model links monthly energy us- age with cooling and heating loads, and latent heat loads. Secondly, temporal data from a building was used to es- timate the overall heat transfer parameters. Thirdly, a clustering scheme was developed to segment all buildings in the portfolio into different clusters based on similar- ity criteria. The overall heat transfer parameters are then separated into different heat transfer coefficients for wall, roof and windowusing data from multiple buildings in the same cluster. We describe an application of this method to K-12 school buildings in the New York City.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Brunswick, Sam</author><author>Dutton, Spencer</author><author>Banks, David</author><author>Adams, Kyle</author><author>Haves, Phil</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A FRAMEWORK FOR ESTIMATING THE POTENTIAL ENERGY SAVINGS OF NATURAL VENTILATION RETROFITS FOR CALIFORNIA COMMERCIAL BUILDINGS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>306-313</pages><keywords/><dates><year>306</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_306.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper proposes an approach for estimating the potential energy savings of retrofitting existing commercial buildings in California for natural ventilation. 308 baseline commercial building models are developed in EnergyPlus based on a characterization of the existing California commercial building stock. Each baseline model and five retrofit options are simulated in the 16 California Climate Zones using TMY3 weather files and energy savings are calculated. Building weights are developed and applied to expand the estimated energy savings to the statewide level. Based on the findings, recommendations will be made to assist policy makers, building designers and owners in making informed decisions regarding the efficacy of natural ventilation retrofits.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zhang, Rui</author><author>Lam, Khee Poh</author><author>Yao, Shi-Chune</author><author>Zhang, Yongjie</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>ANNUAL COUPLED ENERGYPLUS AND COMPUTATIONAL FLUID DYNAMICS SIMULATION OF NATURAL VENTILATION</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>314-321</pages><keywords/><dates><year>314</year></dates><isbn>03601323</isbn><accession-num>89896793</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.buildenv.2013.04.002</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_314.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0360132313001029</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Can coupled Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) and Building Energy Simulation (BES) be used to con- duct annual simulation? This paper tries to investigate the feasibility of annual coupled simulation of CFD and BES. Energy modeling approaches have continued to ad- vance to cater for emerging new design concepts towards “greener” solutions that optimize energy consumption in buildings while maintaining thermal comfort as well as healthy environment. Various efforts have been made to improve the fidelity of the thermal simulation in buildings such as to couple CFD with lumped nodal BES model. Research has shown that the coupled simulation improves simulation accuracy. However, due to the nature of CFD simulation, coupled simulation usually takes much longer computation time. For example, the annual simulation of natural ventilation, which has relatively fewer incidences of CFD simulation runs, would take up to 46 days. In ad- dressing the issue, a coupled lumped heat transfer model (EnergyPlus) and CFD model (Fluent) was implemented, and 8 days of simulation was conducted. Delaunay Tri- angulation based interpolation model was built from the 8 days’ results, which can be used to predict the airflow rates for openings for an annual simulation. It is shown that the interpolation model is able to predict 35% of the natural ventilation deployable time annually, when natu- ral ventilation is appropriate in the Philadelphia climate context. The interpolation model reduces the simulation time by 90%</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hult, Erin L.</author><author>Iaccarino, Gianluca</author><author>Fischer, Martin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>USING CFD SIMULATIONS TO IMPROVE THEMODELING OFWINDOW DISCHARGE COEFFICIENTS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>322-328</pages><keywords/><dates><year>322</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_322.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Accurate parameterization of flow through window openings is necessary in order to model passive and mixed-mode ventilation strategies using airflow network models and energy simulation tools. In these tools, lit- tle guidance is typically provided on selecting airflow pa- rameters such as the discharge coefficient for windows. Detailed computationalfluid dynamics (CFD) simulations can provide an inexpensive, flexible method for develop- ing such parameterizations. In this study, the discharge coefficient for pivoted windows is considered, using an- alytical and CFD modeling as well as comparison with previous data. The discharge coefficient parameteriza- tion currently used in EnergyPlus can lead to an under- estimate of flow through pivoted windows by up to fac- tor of 2. This parameterization for the discharge coeffi- cient as a function of window angle and aspect ratio is modified, and Reynolds-averaged numerical simulations are used to validate this new formulation. Analytical and numerical results compare well with measurements from windowmanufacturers.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zhang, Rui</author><author>Lam, Khee Poh</author><author>Yao, Shi-Chune</author><author>Zhang, Yongjie</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>COUPLED ENERGYPLUS AND COMPUTATIONAL FLUID DYNAMICS NATURAL VENTILATION SIMULATION</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>329-336</pages><keywords/><dates><year>329</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_329.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.ibpsa.us/simbuild2012/Papers/SB12_TS05b_3_Zhang.pdf</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Energy modeling approaches have continued to ad- vance to cater for emerging new design concepts to- wards“greener” solutions that optimize energy consump- tion in buildings while maintaining thermal comfort as well as healthy environment. Increasing attention is given to passive and mix-mode systems in building. Compu- tational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) model has been widely adopted as effective tool for natural ventilation simula- tions. However, CFD become unstable for conjugate heat transfer model, which is the transient heat transfer be- tween solid, e.g., walls, and fluid, e.g., air. Solid and fluid has different respond times. Typically walls respond in hours, and air responds in seconds, causing the system to become stiff. In addressing the issue, a coupled lumped heat transfer model (EnergyPlus) and CFD model (Flu- ent) was implemented, and 8 days of simulation was con- ducted. The airflowrates of openings from the airflownet- work module in EnergyPlus and airflow rates from CFD model were compared. Results show that airflow network model generally predict smaller airflowrates for the open- ings. Airflow network model generates better results for openings on the south and east facade and internal open- ings, with difference ranging from −100% to −200%.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Keller, John L.</author><author>Khuen, Charles A.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A NEW CLIMATE &amp; HOURLY DATA DELIVERY SYSTEM PROVIDING GLOBAL SUPPORT FOR PRECISION MODELING AND CONTROL</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>337-344</pages><keywords/><dates><year>337</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_337.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The need for precision data to support building perfor- mance is growing exponentially, yet the quality and availability of weather data has not changed in decades. We present a new online weather data service with im- mediate access to precision, localized weather history, current conditions and forecasts. The localized weather is created by integrating all available ground station observations with high-resolution datasets from NOAA from 1/1979 through seven-day forecasts. The system also accepts input from on-site private sensor(s). It is designed to support modeling and on-going monitoring, predicted vs. actual performance and to enable advanc- es in monitoring and predictive control. The quality of the output has been verified in comparisons with sites with multiple weather stations.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lee, Benjamin D.</author><author>Sun, Yuming</author><author>Hu, Huafen</author><author>Augenbroe, Godfried</author><author>Paredis, Christiaan J. J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A FRAMEWORK FOR GENERATING STOCHASTIC METEOROLOGICAL YEARS FOR RISK-CONSCIOUS DESIGN OF BUILDINGS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>345-352</pages><keywords/><dates><year>345</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_345.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Current performance-based design of buildings is predominantly based on deterministic simulation, but it is being increasingly recognized that the analysis of uncertainty and risk is important for project success, especially in the design of ultra-low energy buildings. As they represent the boundary conditions in energy simulation, weather data significantly affect model outcomes, so the uncertainty of the meteorological conditions should be taken into account in a risk- conscious design process. In the United States, Typical Meteorological Years are used extensively in the analysis of building energy performance, though they fail to account for any variation from typical weather conditions. This paper seeks to address this issue through the stochastic modeling of meteorological data as a Vector Auto-Regressive (VAR) process with seasonal non- stationarity. We present a framework that characterizes the VAR process using historical meteorological data for any given location. Once defined, the VAR process is able to generate any number of Stochastic Meteorological Years (SMY) for use in simulation packages. The framework is validated with a case study examining predictions of the energy-performance of a solar decathlon competition home.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, Bing</author><author>Dogan, Timur</author><author>Pal, Debashree</author><author>Reinhart, Christoph</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>SIMULATING NATURALLY VENTILATED BUILDINGS WITH DETAILED CFD- BASED WIND PRESSURE DATABASE</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>353-360</pages><keywords/><dates><year>353</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_353.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Natural ventilation has long been recognized as a sustainable design strategy to replace or reduce energy associated with fans or active cooling systems in buildings. When it comes to designing a passive system based concept that involves natural ventilation, a major difficulty for design teams is to reliably predict indoor ventilation rates especially in buildings located in a dense urban context. This manuscript proposes a new concept to model ventilation rates and hourly annual indoor temperature distributions using a combination of outside CFD (Computational Fluid Dynamics) calculations and indoor airflow network calculations. In the first step, CFD calculations for eight cardinal wind directions are used to populate a custom database of pressure coefficients for each window in an urban scene. In the second step, hourly wind data and pressure coefficients method have been implemented in Rhinoceros 1 in combination with Phoenics 2 and EnergyPlus3. Example results are presented for several typical cases, indicating the improvement of this workflow on simulation results, especially for building with particular shape and urban context.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ko, Won Hee</author><author>Schiler, Marc</author><author>Kensek, Karen</author><author>Simmonds, Peter</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>TILTED GLAZING IN BUILDING SIMULATIONS AND ITS EFFECT ON FORM- REFINEMENT OF COMPLEX FACADES</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>361-368</pages><keywords/><dates><year>361</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_361.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Contemporary high-rise buildings can have complex façade configurations, but existing building simulation programs may not have either the capability or user- friendliness to help architects make better decisions early in the design process that could reduce energy use for these forms. This is especially true with faceted and curvilinear building facades where the glazing is not necessarily vertical. Building codes and software often cannot handle these more unusual curtain wall constructions and dynamic geometries. Consideration of these aspects will become increasingly important as parametric forms become more common. Advances in technology have been improving the building design process. One of the important competencies of building professionals is controlling the tremendous amount of data and information that is now associated with buildings. Intelligent software programs allow architects to study design parameters in the design phase, and some of the programs can even suggest design solutions. The ability to use the appropriate software programs and integrate them with design intuition has become one of the most important criteria for a technology-savvy architect in the burgeoning filed of computational design. This paper focuses on tilted glazing and the effect of its angular dependence on direct solar heat gain (DSHG). Spreadsheet calculations were conducted, and the results were linked to an algorithm developed in Grasshopper to demonstrate form refinement of faceted building facades with an emphasis on the angle-dependent DSHG of glazing. This tool can be used at the outset of design or later as one of the components of an energy simulation program where architects can fine tune their initial ideas for the massing of a building. It can help them determine a better tilt angle of glazing for the building and its overall geometry in a specific climate.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hale, Elaine</author><author>Macumber, Daniel</author><author>Benne, Kyle</author><author>Goldwasser, David</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>SCRIPTED BUILDING ENERGY MODELING AND ANALYSIS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>369-376</pages><keywords/><dates><year>369</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_369.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Building energy modeling and analysis is currently a time-intensive, error-prone, and nonreproducible process. From mundane file management tasks, to repeated entry of model parameters, to the application of often-used design transformations, to the execution of large-scale analyses, workflow automation via user- defined scripts has the potential to reduce costs and improve the quality of energy modeling. Many sophisticated building energy modelers already know this and regularly create various scripts to automate portions of their workflows; however, each practitioner must create custom solutions from scratch, which lead to new inefficiencies and potential errors. This paper describes the scripting platform of the OpenStudio tool suite (http://openstudio.nrel.gov) and demonstrates its use in several contexts. Two classes of scripts are described and demonstrated: measures and free-form scripts. Measures are small, single-purpose scripts that conform to a predefined interface. Because measures are fairly simple, they can be written or modified by inexperienced programmers. Because measures have a known interface, they can be shared among users and selected for use at several places in the OpenStudio tool chain. We demonstrate the use of measures in an interactive mode from the OpenStudio SketchUp plug-in and in a noninteractive mode from the OpenStudio application. More experienced users can design and write free-form scripts to automate their work. We demonstrate the advantages of conducting large-scale analysis using free-form scripts through a case study. Finally, a vision for future work in which measures are shared through online libraries is described.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bosworth, David E.</author><author>Pratt, Kevin B.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>NEW METHODS FOR THE CONSTRUCTION AND INTERPRETATION OF HIGH DIMENSIONAL PARAMETRIC BUILDING ENERGY MODELS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>377-384</pages><keywords/><dates><year>377</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_377.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper explores a new method for providing designers with relevant, comprehensible information about potential design variation at appropriate stages in the design process. We propose leveraging both modern CAD software, which allows digital models to be controlled parametrically, and modern computational architectures, which allow access to massive amounts of computing cycles through the use of computation clusters and clouds, to quickly create, enumerate, simulate and analyze large populations of design alternatives. Analysis of these populations is accomplished through the use of both graphical and statistical treatment of the simulation output.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Coffey, Brian</author><author>Tuhus-Eubrow, Dan</author><author>Munshi, Madhav</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>All the ways of meeting a target : Calculating a solution surface using GenOpt</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>385-389</pages><keywords/><dates><year>385</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_385.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Energy efficiency consultants are often asked to find a variety of ways of meeting an energy target, from which the client would select the most suitable by considering installation costs, aesthetics and other concerns. Clients are usually presented with just a few discrete options, but in most cases there are actually infinite ways of meeting the target. Given an n-dimensional space of options de- fined by n design parameters, the set of options that ex- actly meet a particular target is generally a surface of n−1 dimensions. This paper describes methods to calculate a grid of solution points on this surface by selecting one design parameter xi, defining a grid of values for the re- maining design parameters (xj,∀j 6= i) and for each grid point using GenOpt to find the value of xi that exactly meets the target (if a solution exists for that grid point). The technique may also be used to describe trade-offs be- tween design parameters around some reference point. A case study is used herein for illustration. The result is a more comprehensive description of options, and can lead to a richer interaction between designer and analyst, and more designer insight into the energy-related aspects of their project.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Luo, Chen</author><author>Marston, Annie</author><author>Baumann, Oliver</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>OPTIMIZATION OF TYPICAL US HVAC SYSTEMS THROUGH IMPROVED CONTROLS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>390-399</pages><keywords/><dates><year>390</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_390.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper presents an analysis of the energy saving potential for a typical US office building by primarily optimizing the control strategies. The resulting efficiency strategies are assumed to be low or no-cost measures and are modeled and analyzed using a whole building simulation (EnergyPlus version 7.0). Conclusions and recommendations are developed for reducing the all-air system energy consumption under the premise of maintaining and even improving the thermal comfort for occupants.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wilkinson, Patrick</author><author>Olmsted, Chris</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>MODELING HVAC OPTIMIZATION CONTROL STRATEGIES FOR HIGH PERFORMANCE BUILDINGS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>400-405</pages><keywords/><dates><year>400</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_400.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>High efficient equipment selections and advance system designs do not necessarily lead to high performance buildings. In order to truly be a high performance building, the building must operate effectively to maximize the potential energy cost savings for the building owner. Producing these high performance building results requires the implementation and proper use of HVAC optimization control strategies. This paper will prove that equipment should be specified through the use of energy simulation optimization to insure that the greatest potential energy savings can be achieved.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cóstola, Daniel</author><author>Blocken, Bert J. E.</author><author>Hensen, Jan L. M.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>ON INTER-MODEL COMPARISON EXERCISES OF WHOLE BUILDING HAM SIMULATION USING THE BESTEST BUILDING</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>406-413</pages><keywords/><dates><year>406</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_406.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper provides a discussion of the results of two inter-model comparison exercises from IEA-Annex 41, where combined heat and moisture transfer was calculated for three variations of the BESTEST building (based on cases 600 and 900 from IEA- ECBCS SHC-Task 12 / IEA-ECBCS Annex 21). Firstly, basic statistical techniques were used to post- process some results of IEA-ECBCS Annex 41, providing confidence intervals in accordance to a certain confidence level. Secondly, the role of moisture (as well as some aspects of the exercises, such as initialization and material properties) was analysed using recently developed and validated prototype software for the coupling of BES and BEHAM. The paper concludes that combined heat and moisture transfer has a minor influence in the temperature distribution, energy demand and peak power load in the three variations of the BESTEST building simulated. However, combined heat and moisture transfer has large influence on the indoor relative humidity of the BESTEST.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mantha, Pallavi</author><author>Arena, Lois B</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A SYSTEMATIC APPROACH TO HYGROTHERMAL MODELING AND COMPLIANCE WITH FAILURE CRITERIA USING WUFI</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>414-422</pages><keywords/><dates><year>414</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_414.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Simulating the prediction of moisture movement and related risk within building envelopes has gained momentum with the increased use of thicker walls, new materials and assemblies. One such simulation software used widely across North America for hygrothermal analysis is WUFI 5.1. As with any other simulator, WUFI 5.1 requires a few basic inputs such as location, orientation, climate and construction. But hygrothermal modeling is not a clear-cut task. The interactions between the macro level inputs and the dependency on molecular make-up and characteristics of materials makes prediction of hygrothermal performance very volatile. This volatility could lead to under or over predicting moisture related risk in building elements. As a part of an ongoing research and monitoring project, the authors’ team evaluated and intends to monitor several different configurations of wall assemblies in multiple climate and moisture zones to determine the accuracy of moisture modeling. The goal is to make recommendations to ensure durable, efficient assemblies. Based on this research, this paper presents a systematic approach to hygrothermal modeling with WUFI 5.1. Methods to determine compliance with existing failure criteria using results from WUFI 5.1 are discussed. General software observations and possible future improvements are suggested.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>D'Avignon, Katherine</author><author>Kummert, Michaël</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>PROPOSED TRNSYS MODEL FOR STORAGE TANK WITH ENCAPSULATED PHASE CHANGE MATERIALS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>423-430</pages><keywords/><dates><year>423</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_423.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Latent heat storage (LHS) using phase change materials (PCM) is a promising avenue to resolve the frequent timing mismatch between energy supply and demand. This paper deals with the modelling and simulation of a versatile thermal energy storage tank filled with encapsulated PCMs of rectangular geometry. A simple model is implemented as a TRNSYS component un a complete building simulation to be used for selecting phase change temperature and testing control strategies. It uses the enthalpy method and assumes phase change occurs over a small temperature range. A comparison of model results to numerical results found in the literature indicates that it can predict the dynamic performance of this type of thermal energy storage (TES) tank with reasonable accuracy during loading and off-loading cycles. Further work, will aim to improve the model and validate it against experimental measurements.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Fallahi, Ali</author><author>Shukla, Nitin</author><author>Kosny, Jan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>NUMERICAL THERMAL PERFORMANCE ANALYSIS OF PCMS INTEGRATED WITH RESIDENTIAL ATTICS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>431-439</pages><keywords/><dates><year>431</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_431.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>During the last decade, following a rapid growth of low-energy building projects, building components using phase change materials (PCMs) have become more popular in North America. As the focus has slowly begun to shift to a new generation of salt hydrates and bio-based PCMs, it is critical to develop new energy models that can describe the true behavior of these PCMs. While thermodynamic models are essential to analyze the impact at different conditions and using different control strategies of building structures which integrate PCMs, there are few whole-building simulation tools containing sufficient numerical algorithms of the detailed physics, which are necessary to provide accurate simulations of the thermodynamic behavior of these structures. In this paper, a whole-building energy modelling program, ESP-r, based on a finite difference method, is utilized to simulate the thermal behavior of different PCM configurations within an attic space of a ranch-style house. This numerical tool is capable of predicting temperature profiles and heat fluxes within different configurations of PCM applications. In order to evaluate the accuracy of the PCM model in ESP-r, the model is first validated with experiments.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Schiendorfer, Alexander</author><author>Zimmermann, Gerhard</author><author>Lu, Yan</author><author>Lo, George</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>FAULT DIAGNOSIS IN HVAC SYSTEMS BASED ON THE HEAT FLOW MODEL</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>440-447</pages><keywords/><dates><year>440</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_440.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Fault Detection and Diagnosis based on the Heat Flow Model (HFM) provides a generic and extensible frame- work for monitoring HVAC systems. It supports the find- ing and fixing of faulty components. During the fault detection phase, measured sensor and control values are used to perform estimations based on the physical prop- erties of the system. Discrepancies of estimated and mea- sured values are collected as a detection failure vector. Di- agnosis seeks to find the most probable cause for the ob- served failures. In HVAC systems, the failures and faults form an m-n relation. Our proposed diagnosis is per- formed with an associative network to map the relations among failures and faults using the inherent fault simula- tion capabilities of the HFM nodes at runtime. The simi- larity of the detection failure vector to the simulated fail- ure vector indicates the probability of the corresponding fault. To find the best method of fault diagnosis, this pa- per examines different similarity metrics for HFM based FDD, including Euclidean distances, Manhattan distance, root of sum of products, Jaccard index, and a table based metric. The effectiveness of the proposed diagnosis ap- proaches is presented with a case study based on a refer- ence implementation using Simulink and Java.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Dong, Bing</author><author>O'Neill, Zheng</author><author>Li, ZhengWei</author><author>Luo, Dong</author><author>Madhusudana, Shashanaka</author><author>Ahuja, Sunil</author><author>Bailey, Trevor</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>AN INTEGRATED INFRASTRUCTURE FOR REAL-TIME BUILDING ENERGY MODELING AND FAULT DETECTION AND DIAGNOSTICS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>448-455</pages><keywords/><dates><year>448</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_448.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>It is common that a building consumes 20% more than its design intent. The inconsistency between design and operation is a driving force. To address this issue, we present an integrated infrastructure for real-time building energy modeling, visualization and energy Fault Detection and Diagnostics (FDD). A building information model (BIM) based database is developed for the purpose of storing building operational, simulation and FDD analysis data. A BIM to building energy modeling (BEM) middleware is developed to automatically generate energy modeling codes. A connector is developed in Building Control Virtual Testbed (BCVTB) which enables the storage of building energy management system (BEMS) data into a BIM based database in real-time fashion. Finally, this infrastructure is implemented in a real-building and continuously performs its data collection and visualization functions.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cai, Jie</author><author>Braun, James E.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>EFFICIENT AND ROBUST TRAINING METHODOLOGY FOR INVERSE BUILDING MODELING</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>456-461</pages><keywords><keyword>icle</keyword></keywords><dates><year>456</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_456.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper expands on a previous approach for inverse building modeling that utilizes a simplified state-space approach. The goal of the current effort is to provide an efficient and robust parameter training methodology, to which several elements are added. Some seasonal effects, such as variation of window transmittance at different times of the year, are taken into consideration and captured during the training process. In addition, a mixed-mode training approach is developed that allows the use of a combination of data obtained when cooling or heating is occurring with the zone temperature under control at setpoint and when the zone temperature is floating during periods of no load. Different search algorithms were tested for learning a “nearly” global optimal model. A multi-start search method was found to be robust and provide good computational efficiency and accurate results. At the end of this paper, this training methodology is implemented for a single zone case study and some results are provided. Figure</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zimmermann, Gerhard</author><author>Lu, Yan</author><author>Lo, George</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>CONTINUOUS COMMISIONING BASED ON EXTENDED FAULT DETECTION AND DIAGNOSIS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>462-469</pages><keywords/><dates><year>462</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_462.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Buildings seldom perform as intended, resulting in energy use much higher than predicted from design. State-of-the-art HVAC fault detection and diagnosis (FDD) systems report component failures that may corrupt energy efficiency, however FDD does not detect component performance degradation and energy waste from poor designed control sequences. This paper introduces energy related extensions to our pre- vious HFM-FDD system, with which energy consump- tion/production is modeled and simulated in HFM (Heat Flow Model) nodes. The inconsistency between simulated energy data and measured data indicates component performance degradation. In addition, al- ternative control strategies (control algorithms, set- points, etc.) are modeled in the HFM simulation engine to test energy optimization opportunities. All energy calculations can be averaged with short term real data histories. Full year energy evaluations can be produced using standard or local weather files. These extensions that include air and water flow nodes support continu- ous commissioning® (CCx) with operation optimiza- tion. The HFM-FDD with energy and control modeling extension is designed as generic as possible, and re- quires minimal engineering efforts because of model based software generation techniques. Results using structure and data from a complex HVAC system of a real building are included.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lee, Young M</author><author>Liu, Fei</author><author>Meliksetian, Estepan</author><author>Snowdon, Jane</author><author>Bobker, Michael</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>K-12 SCHOOL BUILDINGS IN NEW YORK CITY</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>470-475</pages><keywords/><dates><year>470</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_470.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>An integrated statistical method for computing energy performance metrics of buildings and visualizing the energy performance through spatial analysis is described. This technique combines the hierarchical multivariate regression models and the Variable Base Degree Day (VBDD) model to compute the overall energy performance indicator, and the energy performance indices of base load, heating load and cooling load for each building in a portfolio. Then the various energy performance metrics in the portfolio are selectively visualized on the associated Geographical Information System (GIS) based heat map. The method provides useful information for accurately assessing energy performance, benchmarking and identifying energy performance improvement opportunities in a large portfolio of buildings. The method has been successfully applied and deployed for K-12 school buildings in New York City.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Steinbock, Jason</author><author>Douglas, Jim</author><author>Gauthier, Julia</author><author>Iacono, Chris</author><author>Niederloh, Adam</author><author>Eijadi, David</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>REALITY IMPACTS ENERGY USE : FROM DREAM TIME TO REAL TIME FOR SIMBUILD 2012 CONFERENCE The Weidt Group , Minnetonka , MN</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>476-483</pages><keywords/><dates><year>476</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_476.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper examines how the operational performance of ten buildings in Iowa compares to design projections after at least one year of operation. The design models were created as part of the Alliant Energy Commercial New Construction program and were used to help building owners and design teams understand the potential energy savings of a wide range of technologies. Utility bills, owner surveys, and field observations were used to update the models to understand the actual energy use in these buildings and the savings realized from the energy efficiency investments. This study describes the value of updating model projections for these ten buildings by connecting operational changes with actual building energy use through the use of energy models. The report discusses the importance of adjusting the baseline used in the comparative analysis evaluation of energy conservation measures. Operational parameters are a key component of building energy use but not governed by energy codes and often change from assumptions made during building design, construction and even the early operation period.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Brugman, Matthew</author><author>Erickson, Paul</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A PROCESS FOR, AND RESULTS FROM, WHOLE CAMPUS ENERGY CONSERVATION BY STATISTICAL EXTRAPOLATION OF CALIBRATED ENERGY MODELS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>484-495</pages><keywords/><dates><year>484</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_484.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Building performance simulation and energy modeling has traditionally been focused upon the accurate modeling of the physical performance realities of a single, distinct building. Many modern institutions such as hospital complexes, higher education campuses, military bases and other large facilities consist of multiple buildings. Demonstrating the energy saving impacts of campus-wide building repairs and upgrades has proven to be a daunting task for a professional community focused upon the modeling of single buildings. The immediate objective of this paper is to describe the methods used for developing the University of North Carolina (UNC) Strategic Demand-Side Energy Plan (SDSEP). The SDSEP allows the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill to identify the energy savings potential for 86 campus buildings from a statistically representative set of 20 buildings. The impact of energy savings within these 20 buildings was modeled using calibrated building energy models in eQuest.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, Weimin</author><author>Zhang, Jian</author><author>Moser, Dave</author><author>Liu, Guopeng</author><author>Athalye, Rahul</author><author>Liu, Bing</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>ENERGY AND COST SAVINGS OF RETRO-COMMISSIONING AND RETROFIT MEASURES FOR LARGE OFFICE BUILDINGS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>496-503</pages><keywords/><dates><year>496</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_496.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper evaluates the energy and cost savings of 7 retro-commissioning measures and 29 retrofit measures applicable to most large office buildings. The baseline model is for a hypothetical building with characteristics of large office buildings constructed before 1980. Each retro-commissioning measure is evaluated against the original baseline in terms of its potential for energy and cost savings, while each retrofit measure is evaluated against the commissioned building. All measures are evaluated in five locations (Miami, Las Vegas, Seattle, Chicago and Duluth) to understand the impact of climate conditions on energy and cost savings. The results show that implementation of the seven operation and maintenance measures as part of a retro-commissioning process can yield an average of about 22% energy use reduction and 14% energy cost reduction. Additionally, widening zone temperature deadband, lowering VAV terminal minimum air flow set points and lighting upgrades are found to be the most effective retrofit measures.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zakrzewski, Thomas</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>THE RENOVATION AND REHABILITATION OF HISTORIC BUILDING ENVELOPES: AN IN-DEPTH BUILDING PERFORMANCE AND THERMAL COMFORT ANALYSIS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>504-512</pages><keywords/><dates><year>504</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_504.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Historic building preservation should not be considered an obstacle to sustainability, they inherently share the fundamental goal of preserving the environment. The renovation and rehabilitation of a building envelope provides a preservation benefit of the embodied value/energy of the historic building. The scope of this paper examines how the architectural preservation of Ludwig Mies van Der Rohe's S.R. Crown Hall, (home to the Illinois Institute of Technology's College of Architecture) has impacted the energy use intensity (EUI) of the building as well as the indoor environmental quality (thermal comfort) of its occupants. S.R. Crown Hall has adapted to many new technologies and ventilation strategies in a recent envelope rehabilitation but at the most fundamental level of the project the original philosophy of Mies' 1954 design of the building had to be maintained (the fabric of the building was regarded as sacrosanct). Advanced building simulation was used to provide an in4depth building performance analysis to derive the EUI of the building and to model the occupant thermal comfort with the use of Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) to simulate internal airflows.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Heo, Yeonsook</author><author>Zhao, Fei</author><author>Lee, Sang Hoon</author><author>Sun, Yuming</author><author>Kim, Jinsol</author><author>Augenbroe, Godfried</author><author>Graziano, Diane</author><author>Guzowski, Leah B.</author><author>Muehleisen, Ralph T.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>SCALABLE METHODOLOGY FOR ENERGY EFFICIENCY RETROFIT DECISION ANALYSIS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>513-520</pages><keywords/><dates><year>513</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_513.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.ibpsa.us/simbuild2012/Papers/SB12_TS08b_3_Heo.pdf</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This paper introduces a scalable methodology that supports energy retrofit decision-making at two levels. The methodology is based on normative energy models to provide objective and transparent benchmarking and assessment. The aggregate-level analysis evaluates the effectiveness of policy and business plans on energy savings by benchmarking the energy performance of a collection of buildings and projecting the effects of different retrofit scenarios over time. The individual- level analysis supports risk-conscious decision-making for building stakeholders by providing explicit information about the energy performance risks associated with specific retrofit alternatives. This paper describes model results for a small set of commercial buildings in the Chicago Loop and findings relevant to the method’s application.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Macdonald, Francesca</author><author>Jost, Romain</author><author>Beausoleil-Morrison, Ian</author><author>Kummert, Michaël</author><author>McDowell, Timothy</author><author>Ferguson, Alex</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Demonstration of the RunTime Coupling between ESPr and TRNSYS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>521-528</pages><keywords/><dates><year>521</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_521.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>A run-time coupling between ESP-r and TRNSYS has been developed to offer the possibility of an integrated simulation environment that simultaneously manages detailed performance prediction of both building physics and energy systems. The co-simulator’s design and implementation are described, together with a series of tests used in its verification. An example of the type of system which can be addressed by the coupling of these tools is demonstrated, and its computational efficiency is assessed.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Nouidui, Thierry Stephane</author><author>Wetter, Michael</author><author>Zuo, Wangda</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>VALIDATION OF THE WINDOW MODEL OF THE MODELICA BUILDINGS LIBRARY</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>529-536</pages><keywords/><dates><year>529</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_529.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper describes the validation of the window model of the free open-source Modelica Buildings library. This paper starts by describing the physical modeling assumptions of the window model. The window model can be used to calculate the thermal and angular properties of glazing systems. It can also be used for steady-state simulation of heat transfer mechanism in glazing systems. We present simulation results obtained by comparing the window model with WINDOW 6 the well established simulation tool for steady-state heat transfer in glazing systems. We also present results obtained by comparing the window model with measurements carried out in a test cell at the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kruis, Neal</author><author>Booten, Chuck</author><author>Christensen, Craig</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>OMPARISON OF ENERGYPLUS AND DOE-2 DETAILED WINDOWHEAT TRANSFER MODELS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>537-544</pages><keywords/><dates><year>537</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_537.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Two commonly used building energy simulation en- gines, EnergyPlus and DOE-2, can differ significantly in their calculations of window heating load. In this paper, the authors identify the issues in the window heat transfer algorithms used in detailed window models, and provide suggested changes to make the calculations more accu- rate. We estimate that up to 82% of the observed differ- ences can be resolved through the suggested changes. The methodology employed for this investigation in- volved programming the algorithms from the respective simulation engines in the Engineering Equation Solver (EES) so that the impact of each proposed change could be investigated and quantified independently.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Otto, Kevin</author><author>Eisenhower, Bryan</author><author>O'Neill, Zheng</author><author>Yuan, Shui</author><author>Mezic, Igor</author><author>Narayanan, Satish</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>PRIORITIZING BUILDING SYSTEM ENERGY FAILURE MODES USING WHOLE BUILDING ENERGY SIMULATION</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>545-553</pages><keywords/><dates><year>545</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_545.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Building failure modes can be defined as the range of possible faults, mistuning, degradation and wear that can occur in building systems. They drive poor operational energy performance that can be achieved as compared to what was expected in design. If the more critical failure modes can be uncovered early in design, they can be mitigated through design changes or monitoring of associated characteristics on parameters such as temperatures, flow rates and pressures. To understand and prioritize failure modes, failures are characterized through mappings to whole building simulation input variables, and then random sampling methods are applied to simulate the building operating under combinations of different failure modes. Reduced order models are then fit to the resulting data to detemine which failure modes are more critical. The approach is demonstrated on a mid-sized office building, comparing a standard and advanced retrofit design.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kim, Donghun</author><author>Braun, James E.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>REDUCED-ORDER BUILDING MODELING FOR APPLICATION TO MODEL-BASED PREDICTIVE CONTROL</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>554-561</pages><keywords/><dates><year>554</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_554.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper presents methods and results for representing the complex thermal network of a building envelope and interior in the form of reduced-order state-space equations that can more easily be applied in model-based predictive and other advanced control approaches. The complexities of heat transfer phenomena through glazings and long wavelength exchanges among walls make the representation difficult. The model employs the net radiosity method for long-wave interaction, one-dimensional transient conduction through walls, conductive and convective coupling between zones, etc. Model order reduction is applied to simplify the state-space representation and case study results are presented.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Dobbs, Justin R.</author><author>Hencey, Brandon M.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>AUTOMATICMODEL REDUCTION IN ARCHITECTURE: AWINDOWINTO BUILDING THERMAL STRUCTURE</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>562-568</pages><keywords/><dates><year>562</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.13140/RG.2.1.2843.6644</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_562.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Reducing building model complexity is currently a heuristic process requiring experience and skill; little progress has been made toward a numerical framework to automate this process. This paper proposes integrating automaticmodel reduction into the design process using a transparentmodel abstraction. Resistor-capacitor network analysis, mapped appropriately to a building information model, can provide the architect with insight into thermal coupling among building elements. Experimental results demonstrate the use of model aggregation to reduce sim- ulation time without significant loss of accuracy</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ahuja, Sunil</author><author>Cliff, Eugene</author><author>Narayanan, Satish</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Reduced-order modeling for control of indoor building airflows</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>569-576</pages><keywords/><dates><year>569</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_569.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>We present computationally tractable tools for mod- eling indoor airflow that are amenable to control de- sign. The model reduction technique used, called bal- anced truncation, requires data from CFD simulations but results in models that are of much smaller dimension, typ- ically O(100). The method also guarantees accurate and stable models. For indoor building airflows and thermal environment, the low-order models are used to address the control prob- lem of disturbance rejection. The disturbances include heat gains from solar radiation, occupants or lights, and changes in ambient temperature. The modeling tech- niques are expected to be relevant primarily to systems equipped with low-energy consumption HVAC terminal units, such as displacement ventilation (DV) or radiant cooling/heating, where the stratified indoor environment and airflows are unsteady, spatially inhomogeneous and whose control is highly sensitive to disturbances. Finally, the proposed tools are demonstrated using two building spaces of different spatial scales, both modeled with a DV system; one, a small conference room, and the sec- ond having a large floor-to-ceiling height. In both the cases, the model-based controller is implemented in the full-order system, and is shown to reject disturbances to ensure robust indoor comfort control.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ghobad, Ladan</author><author>Place, Wayne</author><author>Hu, Jianxin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>HE IMPACT OF SYSTEMS INTEGRATION ON THE DAYLIGHTING PERFORMANCE OF SKYLIGHTS IN OFFICES</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>577-584</pages><keywords/><dates><year>577</year></dates><isbn>9781622760923</isbn><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_577.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper focuses on evaluating and optimizing certain features of skylight roofing systems as applied to office buildings. It is the first step in a longer-term research effort on the design, evaluation, and optimization of Roof Daylighting Systems (RDS) in office buildings, which will correlate architectural design features and parameters with illumination quantity and quality and overall energy performance. The primary tools in the study will be Radiance and Daysim for illumination performance (as enabled by Diva for Rhino), and Energy plus for understanding thermal performance. This research will be the focus of several papers and will culminate in the dissertation of the lead author on this paper.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Guglielmetti, Rob</author><author>Scheib, Jennifer</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>CHALLENGES TO INTEGRATED DAYLIGHTING AND ELECTRIC LIGHTING SIMULATION METHODS IN A WHOLE-BUILDING ENERGY SIMULATION CONTEXT</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>585-594</pages><keywords/><dates><year>585</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_585.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>We review current daylight and electric lighting simulation algorithms and their embodiment in some simulation tools and methodologies available to high- performance building engineers and designers. We propose a common set of terms to describe simulation approaches and identify the technology gaps that limit the integrated simulation of daylighting designs. We argue that integration is essential to elevating daylighting to a “keystone strategy” in high- performance and net-zero building design and describe a novel software tool (OpenStudio (Guglielmetti, et al. 2011)) that is being developed to fill the gaps.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jones, Nathaniel L .</author><author>Greenberg, Donald P .</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>ARDWARE ACCELERATED COMPUTATION OF DIRECT SOLAR RADIATION THROUGH TRANSPARENT SHADES AND SCREENS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>595-602</pages><keywords><keyword>build</keyword></keywords><dates><year>595</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_595.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Perforated and transparent shading devices can greatly reduce the amount of incident solar radiation on a building, but they present many challenges for building energy modeling. This paper describes two new methods for calculating direct solar gains on surfaces in geometrically complex environments. One handles shading surfaces containing irregular openings and intricate perforated patterns, while the other handles transparent shading surfaces. Both use fast shader programs written for graphics hardware to account for the effect of the shading surface’s solar incidence angle on light transmission. The two methods can be used alone, together, or in conjunction with other shading algorithms. The effectiveness of these methods is graphically demonstrated on schematic design level architectural CAD models of real buildings with intricate shading devices. These fast algorithms allow the user to rapidly simulate thermal loads in EnergyPlus and compare the effects of many design alterations.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ali, Ahmed A. M.</author><author>Ahmed, Tarek M. F.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>EVALUATING THE IMPACT OF SHADING DEVICES ON THE INDOOR THERMALCOMFORT OF RESIDENTIAL BUILDINGS IN EGYPT</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>603-612</pages><keywords/><dates><year>603</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_603.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The building and spaces shape have a great impact on indoor temperature. Well-Designed sun control and shading devices can dramatically affect indoor temperature. The thermal performance of internal spaces in hot arid desert is highly influenced by various passive design techniques, e.g. space dimensions, facade colors, fenestration ratio, glazing type; and vertical and horizontal shading devices. Simulation tools play an important role in taking decision during early design phase that could help in improving the thermal performance of buildings. The aim of this paper is to explore the impact of different shading devices on the thermal performance of residential buildings in Egypt. To achieve this aim of the research first, the climatic analysis of New Assiut City is introduced followed by identification for the prevailing residential prototypes within the city and the selected residential type. Second, the role of the used Performance simulation tool in enhancing the designs is highlighted. Finally, a simulation has been run for the selected residential site in NA City for the four principal orientations. The results of the study showed that the use of vertical fins have a indoor overhang reduced the temperature by 1.5°C for the temperature for the southern orientation .</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Dogan, Timur</author><author>Reinhart, Christoph</author><author>Michalatos, Panagiotis</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>URBAN DAYLIGHT SIMULATION CALCULATING THE DAYLIT AREA OF URBAN DESIGNS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>613-620</pages><keywords/><dates><year>613</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_613.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper describes the development of a new tool that allows designers to simulate and evaluate the daylight potential of urban master plan proposals. The tool is a plug-in for the Rhinoceros3D CAD modeler and follows a two-step workflow. During the initial step, hourly solar radiation levels on all facades within an urban scene are simulated based on Radiance/Daysim. During the second step, exterior radiation levels are converted into hourly interior illuminance distributions using a generalized impulse response. Climate based daylighting metrics, such as daylight autonomy, are also computed. The results yielded by the new method are carefully compared to regular and substantially more time-consuming Daysim simulations. This comparison shows that the overall daylit area in the investigated master plan matches Daysim predictions within 10%. Given its implementation into the Rhinoceros3D environment, as well as the almost instant simulation feedback, the tool may serve as a generative method for designers.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Raines, Krista</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>PERFORMANCE MODELING FOR A SUSTAINABLE MASTER PLAN</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>621-627</pages><keywords/><dates><year>621</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_621.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper describes building modeling techniques used to analyze sustainable design solutions for a Master Plan in the hot-humid climate of Jakarta. Through analysis, fundamental environmental issues are addressed and key strategies are identified in order to construct design guidelines for a sustainable development. Many environmental issues were identified for the site, but this paper focuses on those analyzed using building energy modeling techniques: mitigating solar heat gain to buildings with optimized massing and block orientation, maximizing air flow and daylight potential through street alignment and width, and optimized shading strategies to prevent heat gain and the urban heat island effect. These strategies result in an aggregate increase in comfort and decrease in the percentage of time cooling is annually required.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jakubiec, J. Alstan</author><author>Reinhart, Christoph F.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>TOWARDS VALIDATED URBAN PHOTOVOLTAIC POTENTIAL AND SOLAR RADIATION MAPS BASED ON LIDAR MEASUREMENTS, GIS DATA, AND HOURLY DAYSIM SIMULATIONS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>628-637</pages><keywords/><dates><year>628</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_628.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>We present a method for generating detailed geometric urban massing models combined with building footprint and material information from large GIS datasets and LiDAR elevation measurements. An example model for the city of Cambridge, Massachusetts, USA that contains over 17,000 buildings is used as input for annual solar radiation calculations using the RADIANCE / DAYSIM simulation engine. Based on hourly irradiance calculation results, we find it possible to make recommendations for PV placement on a building and to intelligently determine the total and useful roof area of buildings. Simulation results are compared to those typically used in practice to produce solar radiation maps of other US cities. It is found that the presented method yields better geometric accuracy and higher irradiation predictions compared to previous methods. This results in increased predicted PV energy production at lower installation costs and more accurate estimates of useful rooftop area.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zhang, Ji</author><author>Heng, Chye Kiang</author><author>Malone-Lee, Lai Choo</author><author>Huang, Yi Chun</author><author>Janssen, Patrick</author><author>Jun, Daniel</author><author>Hii, Chung</author><author>Nazim, Ibrahim</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>PRELIMINARY EVALUATION OF A DAYLIGHT PERFORMANCE INDICATOR FOR URBAN ANALYSIS : FACADE VERTICAL DAYLIGHT FACTOR PER UNIT FLOOR AREA</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>638-646</pages><keywords/><dates><year>638</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_638.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Daylight potential for interior spaces has been one of the primary concerns of building performance simulation and various performance indicators have been proposed for interior daylighting quality evaluation. However, interior daylight simulation on urban scale is time consuming and might be affected by a variety of factors. There is the need for measurement on urban scale that can provide relatively efficient and precise estimation of interior daylight potential. A daylight performance indicator for urban analysis was proposed: facade Vertical Daylight Factor per unit floor area, which is calculated as area- weighted total facade Vertical Daylight Factor divided by total floor area. Numerical simulation was conducted across 20 generic forms and 4 different density scenarios. The results showed a strong and positive correlation between the proposed indicator and the reference indicator of interior daylight potential, i.e. area-weighted average horizontal Daylight Factor at work plane height. The utility of the proposed daylight performance indicator lies in its efficiency of simulation for urban scale of analysis and, therefore, the impacts of geometry, spatial arrangement and envelope material properties of urban built forms on interior daylight potential can be evaluated efficiently in the early planning stage. The limitations of this study and potential future explorations are also addressed.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, Liping</author><author>Haves, Philip</author><author>Buhl, Fred</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>AN IMPROVED SIMPLE CHILLED WATER COOLING COIL MODEL</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>647-654</pages><keywords/><dates><year>647</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_647.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The accurate prediction of cooling and dehumidification coil performance is important in model-based fault detection and in the prediction of HVAC system energy consumption for support of both design and operations. It is frequently desirable to use a simple cooling coil model that does not require detailed specification of coil geometry and material properties. The approach adopted is to match the overall UA of the coil to the rating conditions and to estimate the air-side and water-side components of the UA using correlations developed by Holmes (1982). This approach requires some geometrical information about the coil and the paper investigates the sensitivity of the overall performance prediction to uncertainties in this information, including assuming a fixed ratio of air- side to water-side UA at the rating condition. Finally, simulation results from different coil models are compared, and experimental data are used to validate the improved cooling coil model.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Betz, Fred</author><author>McNeill, James</author><author>Talbert, Bill</author><author>Thimmanna, Harshana</author><author>Repka, Norbert</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>ISSUES ARISING FROM THE USE OF CHILLED BEAMS IN ENERGY MODELS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>655-667</pages><keywords/><dates><year>655</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_655.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Chilled beam technology has seen increasing deployment throughout the United States during the past few years as designers seek the means to address larger sensible cooling demands without increasing duct sizes. While passive and active chilled beams work by basic principles well understood by engineers, their deployment in energy modeling software is often problematic or even erroneous. Active chilled beams have been the most commonly discussed type in the modeling community and our design experience has found these to be the most commonly applied as well. Active chilled beam model workarounds exist for the most commonly used simulation tools for the active chilled beams and tend to be based around induction units. Our experience has been that the magnitude of the simulated energy use results can seem reasonable, so many modelers stop there, though detailed review of hourly reports suggests that the various system components often aren’t acting as the system is intended to operate. The perception of appropriate savings is just that, a perception, albeit misguided. This paper focuses on the differences of the design of actual chilled beam systems versus how they are modeled in eQuest, EnergyPlus, IES-VE, Trane TRACE, and TRNSYS rather than on the results of each software.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Corney, Andrew</author><author>Gardiner, Simon</author><author>Jansen, Connor</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A REVIEW OF HOW DIFFERENT ENERGY ANALYSIS TOOLS ADDRESS VENTILATION IN COMPLEX VAV HVAC SYSTEMS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>668-675</pages><keywords/><dates><year>668</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_668.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Variable Air Volume (VAV) Heating Ventilation and Air Conditioning (HVAC) systems are common design solutions for large buildings with complex zone arrangements. In designing and analyzing these systems, it was found that where the building has large high occupancy center zones combined with a range of perimeter conditions, it is very easy to build an energy model that meets the ventilation code but that might not be supplying enough outside air to maintain CO2 levels below a reasonable setpoint. This paper explores whether this is leading us to underestimate the energy of these systems and offers a review of analysis methods that may enable more accurate asssessment of performance.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Webster, Tom</author><author>Hoyt, Tyler</author><author>Lee, Edwin</author><author>Daly, Allan</author><author>Feng, Dove</author><author>Bauman, Fred</author><author>Schiavon, Stefano</author><author>Lee, Kwang Ho</author><author>Pasut, Wilmer</author><author>Fisher, Dan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>INFLUENCE OF DESIGN AND OPERATING CONDITIONS ON UNDERFLOOR AIR DISTRIBUTION (UFAD) SYSTEM PERFORMANCE</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>676-683</pages><keywords/><dates><year>676</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_676.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.ibpsa.us/simbuild2012/Papers/SB12_TS10b_4_Webster.pdf</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Various methods are used to design and operate underfloor air distribution (UFAD) systems. There are a number of factors that affect UFAD performance: air distribution strategies in the supply plenum, system configuration and diffuser types, slab insulation, air handler supply temperature setpoints, operation of blinds at peak conditions, impact of occupant control, and the effect of climate differences. Generally, these factors influence performance indicators, such as plenum “thermal decay” (supply air temperature gains) and room air temperature stratification, which in turn affect system energy use and comfort conditions. Previously, the impact of design and operating strategies has been difficult to evaluate analytically due to the lack of simulation tools that accurately model the complex heat transfer processes involved with thermal decay and stratification. The development of EnergyPlus along with the recent addition of the UFAD module has progressed to the point that a systematic comparison of these strategies is now possible. In this paper, we take a detailed look at the impact of a number of design and operating variations for a medium office building prototype in Sacramento CA. A comparison to a baseline conventional VAV overhead (OH) system is included to understand better the potential energy and comfort differences between the two technologies.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kim, Hyojin</author><author>Baltazar, Juan-Carlos</author><author>Habberl, Jeff</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>COST-EFFECTIVE RECOMMENDATIONS FOR 15% ABOVE CODE ENERGY EFFICIENCY MEASURES BASED ON THE ASHRAE 90.1-2007 FOR SMALL OFFICE BUILDINGS IN TEXAS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>684-691</pages><keywords/><dates><year>684</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_684.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This paper presents cost-effective recommendations for achieving 15% above-code energy performance, which are based on the ASHRAE Standard 90.1-2007, for commercial small office buildings across the State of Texas. The recommendations were developed for three ASHRAE 90.1-2007 climate zones in Texas along with simple payback calculations. A total of 16 measures were selected, including building envelope and fenestration, HVAC system, service hot water (SHW) system, lighting and receptacle, and renewable options. The implementation costs of each individual measure were calculated along with simple payback calculations. These measures were then combined to achieve a total source energy savings for the group that is 15% above the base-case, ASHRAE 90.1-2007 code- compliant building. Three combinations were proposed in each climate zone with the corresponding payback periods and NOx, SOx, and CO2 emissions savings.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hendricken, Liam</author><author>Otto, Kevin</author><author>Wen, Jin</author><author>Gurian, Patrick</author><author>Sisson, William</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>CAPITAL COSTS AND ENERGY SAVINGS ACHIEVED BY ENERGY CONSERVATION MEASURES FOR OFFICE BUILDINGS IN THE GREATER PHILADELHIA REGION</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>692-706</pages><keywords/><dates><year>692</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_692.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Building stakeholders often need to evaluate energy conservation measure (ECM) retrofit packages to reduce the cost of ownership and energy consumption. The considered alternatives are often ad-hoc and limited to familiar measures. To develop a more systematic evaluation of retrofit options, we study the impact of a wide set of ECMs in combinations as retrofit packages, and assess which combinations offer the most energy conservation for a given investment. We utilize EnergyPlus to evaluate the effectiveness of ECM packages in reducing energy use intensity, and use RSMeans to evaluate the costs of each package. We consider medium office buildings in the Greater Philadelphia region, because this sector offers high potential to reduce building energy consumption in the region. For any level of energy consumption reduction, we find there are several alternative packages of ECMs with varying costs. We identify the least cost alternatives for all levels of energy consumption reduction, and compare these against previous recommendations. This effort is part of an ongoing effort of the Greater Philadelphia Innovation Cluster (GPIC) HUB to create such analyses for common building types in the region.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kirney, Chris</author><author>Parekh, Anil</author><author>Paget, Keith</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>BUILDING ENVELOPE OPTIMAZATION METHOD AND APPLICATION TO THREE HOUSE TYPES IN A PROPOSED SOLAR DISTRICT ENERGY SYSTEM</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>707-714</pages><keywords/><dates><year>707</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_707.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>A simple cost optimization method was applied to determine the appropriate investment in energy efficiency for houses to be built as part of a large scale solar community planned for construction near Calgary, Alberta. The cost effectiveness of individual house envelope energy efficiency upgrades was determined using energy simulation results and builder contributed costing information. These results then guided the combination of house energy efficiency upgrades. Finally, the incremental costs of these combined upgrades were compared to the estimated incremental cost of providing space heating using the planned solar district heating system to determine the appropriate house energy efficiency upgrades.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Campano, Miguel A.</author><author>Domínguez, Samuel</author><author>Fernández-agüera, Jesica</author><author>Sendra, Juan J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>APPLICATION OF INTEGRATED BUILDING SIMULATION AND CFD TO A CLASSROOM HEATING CASE STUDY IN A MEDITERRANEAN CLIMATE</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>715-722</pages><keywords/><dates><year>715</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_715.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This study develops knowledge of the methodological analysis of indoor air distribution in high density rooms, allowing evaluation of the expected comfort level of the occupants. A typical classroom is presented as a case study, focusing on the influence of dedicated ventilation. The methodology established the boundary conditions using discretization and determination of values over time which defined the dynamic energy behaviour of the room, by means of a nodal model. The study incorporates sectional isothermal curves and air velocity analysis, the use of indicators to evaluate the thermal comfort of the occupants according to ASHRAE standards, and comparisons of alternative HVAC systems. A case study application shows poor efficiency of traditional radiator heating systems versus those which incorporate a neutral ventilation air supply.</abstract></record><record><database name="simbuild2012.enl" path="simbuild2012.enl">simbuild2012.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Muehleisen, Ralph T.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>SIMPLE DESIGN TOOLS FOR EARTH-AIR HEAT EXCHANGERS</title><secondary-title>SB2012</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>SB2012</full-title></periodical><pages>723-730</pages><keywords/><dates><year>723</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://SB2012_723.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>In the early stages of the design of building systems, the use of simple design tools can help estimate the size and/or impact of system components in evaluating the viability of various technologies. However, such design tools are not readily available to evaluate earth-air heat exchangers (EAHEs), also known as earth-tubes. Furthermore, even though many researchers have developed sophisticated equations to analyze EAHEs, they cannot be easily recast into design equations and must be used by trial-and-error. This paper describes a set of simplified analysis and design equations to support early-stage EAHE design and which are suitable for implementation in a spreadsheet. The equations we have developed allow the designer to quickly determine the length of tubing required for a desired level of heat transfer effectiveness; estimate the pressure drop across the system and required fan power; and estimate the mean monthly temperature of air exiting the tube.</abstract></record></records></xml>
