title: SimBuild 2012 Conference Progam 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97048>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96ec8>
pages: 0
abstract: Program for SimBuild 2012
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_2012.pdf
filename: SB2012_2012.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_2012.pdf

title: REAL-TIME RESOLUTION OF CONFLICTING OBJECTIVES IN BUILDING ENERGY 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc96f48>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96c08>
pages: 1-8
abstract: We present an utopia-tracking multiobjective optimiza- tion strategy to resolve conflicting objectives in real-time energy management. Conflicts arise frequently from the need to balance economic and noneconomic metrics such as energy demand and occupant comfort. We demon- strate that the proposed approach leads to better perfor- mance compared with the traditional weighting approach. In particular, we demonstrate that improper adjustment of weights can lead to large excursions in performance. The proposed approach automatically locates the opti- mal weights and does not require the computation of the Pareto front, making it ideal for real-time implementation.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_1.pdf
filename: SB2012_1.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_1.pdf

title: A TWO-STAGE SIMULATION-BASED ON-LINE OPTIMIZATION SCHEME FOR HVAC DEMAND RESPONSE 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc971c8>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc973c8>
pages: 9-16
abstract: The on-line control optimization for building heating, ventilation and air conditioning (HVAC) systems is crucial for automatic demand response. Simulation- based optimization techniques usually require intensive computation, even with advanced optimization algorithms, and therefore are not feasible for on-line decision making. This article presents a two-stage scheme in which an “optimal strategy pool” is generated by off-line optimization on the identified weather patterns. And only a small number of strategies are subject to on-line simulation evaluation. This two- stage approach shows superior capability of identifying optimal DR strategies and reducing on-line computation load, simultaneously. A case study with EnergyPlus simulation of a large education facility at Berkeley, CA is included.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_9.pdf
filename: SB2012_9.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_9.pdf

title: MULTI-OBJECTIVE OPTIMIZATION MODEL FOR BUILDING RETROFIT STRATEGIES 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97408>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc974c8>
pages: 17-24
abstract: In face of the multiple choices for retrofitting a building, the main issue is to identify those that prove to be the most effective in the long term. In this work, a simulation-based multi-objective optimization scheme (a combination of TRNSYS, GenOpt and a Tchebycheff optimization technique developed in MATLAB) is employed to minimize energy use in the building in a cost effective manner, while considering the occupant’s requirements. In order to achieve the best compromise solutions a wide decision space is considered, including alternative materials for external wall insulation, roof insulation, different window types, and installation of solar collector in the existing building. An existing house needing retrofit is taken as a case study and the effectiveness of the approach is demonstrated for identifying a number of Pareto optimal solutions for building retrofit. The results verify the practicability of the approach and highlight potential problems that may arise.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_17.pdf
filename: SB2012_17.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_17.pdf

title: A PARAMETRIC STUDY OF THE THERMAL PERFORMANCE OF DOUBLE SKIN FAÇADES AT DIFFERENT CLIMATES USING ANNUAL ENERGY SIMULATION 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc96cc8>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96e88>
pages: 211-218
abstract: This research analyzes the thermal performance of several types of Double Skin Façades [DSF] to determine which are best suited for each climate zone. The purpose of the research is to help guide project owners and unspecialized architects during their decision making process, when they choose to design a DSF. Using Building Energy Modeling [BEM] software, various types of naturally ventilated DSFs are analyzed in all seventeen ASHRAE climate zones. The thermal performance of the DSF is determined by comparing the building energy use data of a generic office building. The different types of DSFs are created following a set of parameters such as stratification type, permissibility of airflow, and width of interstitial space.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_21.pdf
filename: SB2012_21.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_21.pdf

title: MAPPING HVAC SYSTEMS FOR SIMULATION IN ENERGYPLUS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97048>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc970c8>
pages: 25-31
abstract: For building energy simulation tools to be accessible to designers, tool interfaces should present a conventional view of HVAC systems to the user, and then map this view to the internal data model used in the tool. The paper outlines a process that enables design engineers to create HVAC system representations using industry standard terminology and system, icon and typological representations and convert that unified representation into the format required by the whole building energy simulation tool EnergyPlus. This paper describes each stage of the conversion process, which involves transformations between the following representations: 1) engineer’s representation, 2) component connectivity representation, 3) representation in the internal data model used in the Simergy graphical user interface for EnergyPlus, and 4) EnergyPlus representation. The paper also describes mappings between these representations and the development of a rule-based validation and assignment framework required to implement that mapping. In addition, the paper describes the implementation of this process in Simergy.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_25.pdf
filename: SB2012_25.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_25.pdf

title: DEVELOPMENT OF A FLEXIBLE , MULTIZONE , MULTIFAMILY BUILDING SIMULATION MODEL 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc96f48>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96f08>
pages: 32-39
abstract: As weatherization of multifamily buildings becomes more widespread, improvement is needed in energy audit tools for multifamily buildings. On the wish list of field experts is the capability to model multizone build- ings (i.e., one thermal zone per dwelling unit) with simplified user input to improve analysis of decentral- ized and centralized HVAC and domestic hot water systems without creating detailed building models. To provide the desired capabilities, development of an enhanced energy audit tool was begun in 2011. The tool is a strategically structured, flexible, one-zone-per-unit DOE-2.1e model coupled with a simplified user inter- face to model small to large multifamily buildings with decentralized or centralized systems and associated energy measures. This paper describes the modeling concept and its implementation.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_32.pdf
filename: SB2012_32.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_32.pdf

title: CREATING ZONING APPROXIMATIONS TO BUILDING ENERGY MODELS USING THE KOOPMAN OPERATOR 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97808>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96cc8>
pages: 40-47
abstract: As the scope of building construction increases and de- signs become more integrated, building energy models have found widespread use in evaluating building per- formance. Despite the growing sophistication of build- ing modelling tools, errors can arise from the approxima- tions that are made during model creation. This paper ad- dresses model zoning, i.e., how the volume of a building is divided into regions where properties are assumed to be uniform. Zoning is important during the creation of a model because the accuracy of prediction from simu- lating a model reduces when dissimilar zones are lumped together. In this paper, a systematic approach to creat- ing zoning approximations is introduced to investigate the effect of zoning on simulation accuracy. Applying the Koopman operator, an infinite-dimensional, linear oper- ator that captures nonlinear, finite-dimensional dynamics without linearization, a detailed building model is stud- ied. Using the Koopman operator, the temperature history of rooms produced by a building simulation can be de- composed into Koopman modes. These modes identify dynamically significant behavior which will form a basis for the creation of zoning approximations. An implemen- tation of this technique is illustrated in a building model of an actual building designed with both mechanical and natural conditioning.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_40.pdf
filename: SB2012_40.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_40.pdf

title: AN INVESTIGATION TO OPTIMIZE THE MECHANICAL SYSTEMS TO MEET COMFORT CRITERIA IN A LARGE ATRIUM 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97688>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96cc8>
pages: 48-55
abstract: A large office building has a 140 m atrium which is split into four sections: atriums 1, 2, and 3 and a “sky garden” which is the upper most atrium with trees and shrubs. The atrium was simulated first in EnergyPlus to obtain the correct surface conditions for the critical days and then in Star CCM+. The first CFD analysis showed uncomfortable temperatures on the upper balconies in each section in the summer months. The optimization of the jet nozzles angles, the additional components and the supply temperature adjustment has shown a promising improvement in the thermal comfort on the balconies.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_48.pdf
filename: SB2012_48.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_48.pdf

title: TOWARDS BETTER MODELING OF RESIDENTIAL THERMOSTATS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc973c8>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96c08>
pages: 56-62
abstract: Thermostats are notorious for being difficult to use. Consequently, heating is manually controlled by occupants in most homes, including those with programmable thermostats. Conventional modeling approaches fail at capturing behavioral elements by relying on fixed setpoint schedules. To accurately assess the energy impact of thermostat operation requires two changes to the way simulations are carried out. First, thermostat setpoint programs must be defined based on how thermostats are actually operated instead of the usually assumed ideal behavior; and second, realistic occupancy schedules must be adopted instead of average schedules. This may require layering of behavioral logic atop thermostat logic. In this paper we present an approach for doing this using Energy Plus and American Time Use Survey (ATUS) data, together with some examples.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_56.pdf
filename: SB2012_56.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_56.pdf

title: APPLICATION OF A STOCHASTIC WINDOW USE MODEL IN ENERGYPLUS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97888>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97708>
pages: 63-70
abstract: Natural ventilation, used appropriately, has the potential to provide both significant HVAC energy savings, and improvements in occupant satisfaction. Central to the development of natural ventilation models is the need to accurately represent the behavior of building occupants. The work covered in this paper describes a method of implementing a stochastic window model in EnergyPlus. Simulated window use data from three stochastic window opening models was then compared to measured window opening behavior, collected in a naturally-ventilated office in California. Recommendations regarding the selection of stochastic window use models, and their implementation in EnergyPlus, are presented.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_63.pdf
filename: SB2012_63.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_63.pdf

title: WINDOW-WALL INTERFACE CORRECTION FACTORS: THERMAL MODELING OF INTEGRATED FENESTRATION AND OPAQUE ENVELOPE SYSTEMS FOR IMPROVED PREDICTION OF ENERGY USE 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc96d48>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96c88>
pages: 71-74
abstract: The boundary conditions for thermal modeling of fenestration systems assume an adiabatic condition between the fenestration system installed and the opaque envelope system. This theoretical adiabatic boundary condition may not be appropriate owing to heat transfer at the interfaces, particularly for aluminum-framed windows affixed to metal-framed walls. In such scenarios, the heat transfer at the interface may increase the discrepancy between real world thermal indices and laboratory measured or calculated indices based on NFRC Rating System.This paper discusses the development of Window-Wall Interface (WWI) Correction Factors to improve energy impacts of building envelope systems.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_71.pdf
filename: SB2012_71.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_71.pdf

title: VIRTUAL MOCK-UP MODELING AS STUDY MODEL OF BUILDING ENVELOPE PERFORMANCE AND DESIGN 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc96f88>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97448>
pages: 75-82
abstract: The current use of mock-ups in building envelope design is to serve as critical milestones in validating the envelope performance. There is increasing emphasis of the importance of physical mock-ups, in particular during pre-construction stages, in emerging guidelines, specifications and building practice methods. However physical mock-ups construe the design process as linear and can exacerbrate the project workflow when problems are discovered through these mock-ups at this late building design phase. To allow for more flexibility and interaction of the mock-up validation process into the re-terative design generation process, an alternate more robust mode of investigation needs to be explored. Virtual mock-ups are economical, less time consuming and robust options to their physical counterpart including their potential to integrate with building information modeling. This paper discusses research conducted on implications of virtual mock-ups and how their implementation, through case studies, was used as study models within an integrated exchange platform.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_75.pdf
filename: SB2012_75.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_75.pdf

title: THERMAL PERFORMANCE OF THREE?DIMENSIONAL BUILDING ENVELOPE ASSEMBLIES AND DETAILS FOR IMPROVING THE ACCURACY OF WHOLE BUILDING PERFORMANCE SIMULATION 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97188>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97448>
pages: 83-95
abstract: Thermal bridging through insulation layers in the building envelope reduces the thermal performance of building envelope assemblies and heat flow through thermal bridging can have a detrimental impact on wholebuilding energy performance. So, it is important for energy modelers, building engineers, and architects to consider the effects of thermal bridging when evaluating the expected performance of building envelope details and when designing building envelopes for energy efficient buildings. However, it is difficult to determine how much heat flows through thermal bridges using typical approaches, such as the areaweighted average of Uvalues, especially when dealing with threedimensional (3D) heat flow paths. In ASHRAE Research Project 1365 (RP1365), a methodology was developed, using a calibrated 3D model, that enables designers to account for heat flow through thermal bridges in a simple and practical manner. This approach can improve the accuracy of whole building performance simulations where complex thermal bridging is often ignored. This paper will provide an overview of RP1365 and its potential impact on energy simulation. The impact on whole building energy performance will be examined for three building types in four different climates
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_83.pdf
filename: SB2012_83.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_83.pdf

title: THE DATABASE OF EGYPTIAN BUILDING ENVELOPES (DEBE): A DATABASE FOR BUILDING ENERGY SIMULATIONS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc96f08>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96c08>
pages: 96-103
abstract: This paper is a part of an ongoing research that aims to describe the influence of building constructions on energy consumption through a survey that is conducted in Cairo and its surrounding residential neighbourhoods. An inventory of the selected neighbourhoods envelope constructions and their characteristics is described in accordance with the new Egyptian energy standard for residential buildings. After thorough screening and classification, the constructions are digitalized and uploaded in an online open source database where constructions properties are listed, made available in .idf and .ddb formats (EnergyPlus and DesignBuilder respectively) and illustrated graphically. This Database of Egyptian Building Envelopes (DEBE) facilitates the input modelling of constructions and enables users to explore standard complying alternative constructions.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_96.pdf
filename: SB2012_96.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_96.pdf

title: SWIMMING POOL HALL HVAC MODELLING, SIMULATION AND END OF SETBACK NEURAL NETWORK PREDICTION: A DETAILED CASE STUDY 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97148>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97908>
pages: 104-111
abstract: This paper presents a novel methodology for applying modelling and simulation techniques to a swimming pool environment aimed at achieving energy savings by optimising the end of setback (EoS) schedule of the heating, ventilation and air conditioning (HVAC) system. The Building Controls Virtual Test-Bed (BCVTB) simulation platform is used to integrate different modelling and simulation tools to improve the accuracy of the simulations while reducing modelling effort. To test the feasibility of using artificial intelligence techniques in optimising the EoS, an application using artificial neural networks (ANN) is developed and discussed. A detailed case study is also presented and discussed.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_104.pdf
filename: SB2012_104.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_104.pdf

title: CONTROL-ORIENTED DYNAMIC MODELING AND CALIBRATION OF A CAMPUS THEATER USING MODELICA 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97a08>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96d48>
pages: 112-119
abstract: In order to design and assess the dynamic performance of building automation systems, accurate control-oriented models are needed. Previous modeling languages do not accurately capture transients and state information to the fidelity that is needed for rigorous control-theoretic analy- sis. With the recent progress in building energy modeling in Modelica, these transients, and the dynamics of the sys- tem in general, can are captured more accurately. In this paper we will discuss necessary methodologies that are needed to construct and calibrate an energy model for the purpose of control system design and tuning. We will dis- cuss topics pertaining to this process including selection of appropriate steady state and dynamic data for model tuning. A case study will be included which investigates the dynamic performance of a building containing a movie theater and acoustic sound stage. Frequency domain con- trol analysis will be presented using the calibrated model
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_112.pdf
filename: SB2012_112.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_112.pdf

title: PRACTICAL TECHNIQUES FOR AUTOMATED CALIBRATION OF EXISTING MODELS FOR USE IN BUILDING OPERATIONS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97a08>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97088>
pages: 120-127
abstract: Building energy models constructed during the design phase can be used during building operations for benchmarking, fault detection and diagnosis, controls optimization and retrofit analysis. For most such applications, the model must be calibrated to at least roughly match measured data. This calibration process can be effectively framed and solved as an error minimization problem by calibration parameters and bounds. Although the final determination of parameter values is algorithmically, there is judgment necessary to set up and solve the problem. This paper demonstrates some practical techniques for setting up and solving the problem with GenOpt, including the iterative process of solving for successively more complete problem statements. Additionally, the paper discusses some of the ways in which modeling expertise plays an important illustrated by reference to recent projects. role, illustrated by reference to recent projects.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_120.pdf
filename: SB2012_120.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_120.pdf

title: COMPARISON OF TWO DIFFERENT SIMULATION PROGRAMS WHILE CALIBRATING THE SAME BUILDING 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97088>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97688>
pages: 128-135
abstract: An existing institutional building of 95,287 square feet was calibrated for energy usage using Design Builder and eQuest. The whole building simulation models were made based on precise building geometry, occupancy, and equipment power and lighting densities. Building schedules were input to more closely relate the digital model to the actual building’s use (occupancy, heating, cooling, lighting, and ventilation), and some on-site measurements of plug loads were taken. Load balance, sizing of systems, electrical and gas consumption, and end uses of fuel consumption are compared. This paper explores the differences between the outputs and workability of both simulation tools. process, the main differences in modeling and simulating in the two software programs were observed and documented.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_128.pdf
filename: SB2012_128.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_128.pdf

title: COMPARATIVE ANALYSIS OF AIR-TO-AIR HEAT PUMP MODELS FOR BUILDING ENERGY SIMULATION Hubert 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97688>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97a48>
pages: 136-143
abstract: The decrease of heat demands in the low energy build- ings requires to reexamine modeling approaches in the building simulation, particularly the dynamic response of the building and its equipments lead to re-examine modeling rules. From a review of air-to-air heat pump models, three types are compared in order to evaluate the ability of each one to predict the energy consumption and power demands. These air-to-air heat pump models coupled to a single zone building are simulated on Modelica. The aim is to underline the advantages and the drawbacks of the different modeling approaches for dynamic simulation in respect of the different phenomena to represent.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_136.pdf
filename: SB2012_136.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_136.pdf

title: AN EVALUATION OF THE EFFECTIVENESS OF PRE-COOLING IN A HYBRID GROUND SOURCE HEAT PUMP 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97b08>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96c88>
pages: 144-151
abstract: Hybrid ground source heat pump (HyGSHP) systems for building heating and cooling are gaining popularity as a means of decreasing long term energy and maintenance costs while maintaining manageable first costs. In these systems there is a potential to use the ground not only as an immediate heat source or sink, but as an energy store. On a scale of hours, the ground store could be cooled by a hybrid component, such as a cooling tower, during the night in order to improve the heat rejection efficiency in cooling during the following day. This paper presents the results of a study of the ground as a thermal energy store on a short term basis.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_144.pdf
filename: SB2012_144.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_144.pdf

title: FEASIBILITY OF COMBINED SOLAR/HEAT PUMP SYSTEMS FOR REDUCED RESIDENTIAL CONDITIONING ENERGY CONSUMPTION 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc978c8>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96f48>
pages: 152-159
abstract: This paper investigates the impact of using an air- source heat pump system in a thermally efficient house for two locations: Chicago, IL and Dallas, TX. In addition to an air-source heat pump, a geothermal heat pump system is implemented in the Chicago location. The source energy savings over a conventional system is reported as well as the life cycle costs for each of these cases. The conventional system is a natural gas furnace and air conditioner. In addition, to improve the performance of the air-source heat pump system, photovoltaics and solar thermal systems are implemented to analyze the effects on the energy savings and life cycle costs.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_152.pdf
filename: SB2012_152.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_152.pdf

title: THE ENERGY SAVING POTENTIAL OF MEMBRANE-BASED ENTHALPY RECOVERY IN VAV SYSTEMS FOR COMMERCIAL OFFICE BUILDINGS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc978c8>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96f88>
pages: 160-167
abstract: A design tool to evaluate the heat and mass transfer effectiveness and pressure drop of a membrane-based enthalpy exchanger was developed and then used to optimize the configuration of an enthalpy exchanger for minimum pressure drop and maximum heat recovery effectiveness. Simulation was used in a parametric study to investigate the energy saving potential of the enthalpy recovery system. The case without energy recovery and air side economizer was used as a baseline. Two comparison cases for the implementation of enthalpy recovery with and without air side economizer were simulated in EnergyPlus. A case using a desiccant wheel for energy recovery was also investigated for comparison purposes. The simulation results show significant energy saving benefits from applying a low pressure drop, high effectiveness enthalpy exchanger in two US cities representing a range of humid climates. The sensitivity of the energy savings potential to pressure drop and heat and mass transfer effectivenesses is also presented.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_160.pdf
filename: SB2012_160.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_160.pdf

title: ZONAL APPROACH TO MODELING THERMALLY STRATIFIED ATRIA 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc96f88>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96e88>
pages: 168-176
abstract: Thermally stratified atria and similar spaces present challenges for building thermal-comfort and energy modeling. This work tests a zonal modeling method for dynamic thermal and energy simulation of a heavily glazed and thermally stratified atrium cooled by displacement ventilation. The goal of the study was to explore the extent to which this method offers any improvement over simpler methods with respect to assessing thermal comfort and energy consumption. This paper describes a thermal and bulk-airflow zonal modeling strategy that appears to capture the some of the principal effects of thermal plumes generated when glazed façades and other interior surfaces are heated by solar radiation. This approach may be applicable to a relatively broad range of projects with similar characte- ristics. A CFD tool running the same model of the space, but without the zonal subdivisions, was used to tune the dynamic thermal/bulk-airflow model and to assess the degree to which the latter provides consis- tently appropriate results with variation in solar gain. The zonal approach appears to have some advantage with respect to predicting thermal comfort as a function of heat removed from the interior of glazed façades; however, a comparison with a simpler method that does not use bulk-airflow modeling suggests that this simpler method may provide much of the same benefit with respect to assessing energy consumption.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_168.pdf
filename: SB2012_168.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_168.pdf

title: STREAMLINED MULTIZONE MODEL CREATION 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97788>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96f08>
pages: 177-184
abstract: Multizone modeling for the simulation of airflow and contaminant transport in buildings is intermediate in resolution and complexity between the extremes represented by single-zone models and computational fluid dynamics. The model input time requirements for a multizone building model are likely less than that required for the construction of computational fluid dynamics model of a building subset, but are likely more than required for a single-zone building model. This paper describes techniques intended to reduce the time required to construct a multizone representation of a building and presents data demonstrating their effectiveness. The airflow network that models the movement of air is constructed semi-automatically from input geometrical information, simple mechanical systems descriptions, and high-level weather parameters. The time required for model construction with this streamlined input procedure is measured using an implementation of the streamlined procedures. Model creation time is found to be approximately one quarter of the time required to construct the same model using standard techniques. When calibrated, the resulting models are sufficiently representative of the buildings under study to be useful for analytical and design studies.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_177.pdf
filename: SB2012_177.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_177.pdf

title: APPLICATION OF A NATURAL VENTILATION SYSTEM DESIGN TOOL TO A SCHOOL BUILDING 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97748>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96f88>
pages: 185-192
abstract: A software tool (LoopDA) to aid in the design of natural ventilation systems has recently been udpated. This update implements a general method for sizing of natural ventilation system components, which allows direct consideration of stack and wind-driven airflow. The tool assists the designer in performing the following steps in developing the natural ventilation system design: establishing the global geometry and topology of zones and interconnecting flow paths, establishing design conditions, setting up and solving the representative loop equations based on the “design” form of the airflow components, and analyzing operation under a variety of conditions. This paper describes the updated tool and provides an example of its application to the design of a naturally ventilated school building.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_185.pdf
filename: SB2012_185.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_185.pdf

title: WIND-DRIVEN NATURAL VENTILATION IN A LOW-RISE BUILDING: A NUMERICAL AND EXPERIMENTAL STUDY 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc96f88>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96c08>
pages: 193-200
abstract: This paper presents a Boundary-Layer Wind Tunnel (BLWT) and numerical study on wind-driven natural ventilation for a low-rise building with multi-room partitioning, variable porosity size openings (in doors, windows and soffits), and a uniformly-distributed background leakage at a model-testing scale of 1:20. For the size of the building and openings considered, the experimental analyses indicated that the internal pressure due to cross-ventilation was 1.5 to 2.5 times higher when the ratio Ainlet/Aoutlet >1 compared to Ainlet/Aoutlet <1 . Room partitioning significantly affected the distribution of internal pressures, and hence the pressure drop, in the particular case considered the room partitioning enhanced the ventilation by breaking the large circulation zones that would have been produced for a single zone. The inlet discharge coefficients obtained in this experiment ranged from 0.65 to 1.08, similar to the results of various early studies. The numerical study further clarified the characteristics of the cross-ventilation with and without room partitioning.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_193.pdf
filename: SB2012_193.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_193.pdf

title: ASSESSING THERMAL BRIDGES IN COMMERCIAL WALL SYSTEMS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc96c08>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96f08>
pages: 201-210
abstract: This paper focuses on the methodology developed utilizing the 2-D heat transfer program THERM to more accurately assess the 3-D heat flow from discontinuous bridging elements. Additionally, the research looks at a number of common connection, and compares the calculated U-values to simulation predictions and installed performance using thermal imaging. The paper will focus on both the methodology used, as well as the finding of the research to better comprehend the deviation in thermal performance between design intentions, simulation, and actual performance.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_201.pdf
filename: SB2012_201.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_201.pdf

title: CONDUCTION TRANSFER FUNCTIONS IN TRNSYS MULTIZONE BUILDING MODEL: CURRENT IMPLEMENTATION, LIMITATIONS AND POSSIBLE IMPROVEMENTS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc973c8>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97748>
pages: 219-226
abstract: The Conduction Transfer Function (CTF) method is used by many building energy performance simulation programs to calculate 1-D transient heat conduction through multi-layer envelope components. TRNSYS is one of these programs, and several authors have reported problems with the current CTF implementation in its multizone building model, known as Type 56. Reported problems are related to heavy and highly insulated slabs and short time-step simulations (less than 15-minute time-step). This paper documents the current implementation of CTF in Type 56. It then reports on our investigation of some issues with the current implementation and their causes. Workarounds and short-term solutions are assessed and longer-term improvements are discussed.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_219.pdf
filename: SB2012_219.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_219.pdf

title: PASSIVHAUS AND NET ZERO ENERGY RESIDENTIAL DESIGNS IN A COLD CLIMATE: A SIMULATION BASED DESIGN PROCESS FOR THE NEXT GENERATION OF GREEN HOMES 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97748>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97ac8>
pages: 227-235
abstract: Today’s residential construction industry is capable of producing exceptionally high performing houses that far exceed compliance with local building codes. We feel that setting a target of Net-Zero Energy (NZE) is feasible in the US considering the design and construction technology available. This paper is part of an extensive project focusing on residential construction utilizing Passivhaus strategies with an emphasis on solar design and a target of Net- Zero energy use. The focus of this paper is on the role of simulation as a design aid in developing guidelines relating to building form, orientation, glazing, and roof area for solar electrical and thermal systems.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_227.pdf
filename: SB2012_227.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_227.pdf

title: PREDICTION OF THE URBAN HEAT ISLAND EFFECT TO BE USED IN BUILDING ENERGY ANALYSES 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97c88>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97408>
pages: 236-245
abstract: The increase in air temperature produced by urban- ization, a phenomenon known as the Urban Heat Island (UHI) effect, is often neglected in current building energy simulation practices. The UHI effect can have an impact on the energy consumption of buildings, especially those with low internal heat gains or with an inherent close interaction with the outdoor environment (e.g. naturally-ventilated buildings). This paper presents an Urban Weather Generator (UWG) to calculate air temperatures inside urban canyons from measurements at an operational weather station located in an open area outside a city. The model is evaluated against field data from Basel (Switzerland) and Toulouse (France). The expected error of UWG predictions is about 1 K, which stays within the range of air temperature variability observed in different locations of the same urban area.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_236.pdf
filename: SB2012_236.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_236.pdf

title: A GIS-BASED ASSESSMENT METHOD FOR MEAN RADIANT TEMPERATURE IN DENSE URBAN AREAS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97d08>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97ac8>
pages: 246-254
abstract: The mean radiant temperature (Tmrt) is among the most important factors affecting thermal comfort. Its assessment in dense cities has been complicated due to the presence of buildings, pavings, and infrastructure. This paper introduced the RAMUM model, a GIS based software method developed to simulate outdoor mean radiant temperature at micro- scale. The advantages of this method lie in its efficiency and resolution that supports the design of buildings, streets, and public open spaces. The model is evaluated using field measurements under cold and warm weather in Boston. This study is sponsored by the EFRI-1038264 award from the National Science Foundation (NSF), Division of Emerging Frontiers in Research and Innovation (EFRI).
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_246.pdf
filename: SB2012_246.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_246.pdf

title: GENERATIVE URBAN MODELING: A DESIGN WORK FLOW FOR WALKABILITY-OPTIMIZED CITIES 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc96d08>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96f48>
pages: 255-262
abstract: This paper presents an urban analysis work flow using a Rhinoceros/Grasshopper massing tool. The tool utilizes terrain elevation models as part of the design process to subdivide sites and generate urban form to be explored parametrically. It can then be linked to various performance assessment methods. As a proof of concept, the study uses a walkability calculator for three urban form alternatives, and applies genetic algorithms to optimize generated designs through allocation of land-use. Results show a great diversity that converges to near optimal solutions. A discussion is drawn about the effort and time spent to model such iterations versus it’s automation using this work flow, and conclusions show the potentials, limitations and directions for future research work.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_255.pdf
filename: SB2012_255.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_255.pdf

title: ENVIRONMENT MAPPING FOR FAST AND ROBUST CALCULATION OF INDIRECT RADIANT ENERGY 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc96d08>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96e88>
pages: 263-269
abstract: Inclusion of site data, such as the surrounding structures, terrain, and vegetation, all of which modulate the amount of indirect radiation exchange between a building and its environment is necessary for accurate building energy simulation. While the impact of indirect radiant energy is potentially large, it is also very time consuming to calculate. Thus building energy simulations tend to incorporate simplified environment models or to omit the indirect radiation calculation altogether. This paper describes how a computer graphics algorithm, environment mapping, can be used to accurately calculate the indirect reflected radiant energy from the environment. We encode the complete panoramic environment surrounding a surface as an image texture that serves as a look-up table parameterized by direction. Different pieces of information such as sky, clouds, and buildings or obstructions are stored in separate textures that can be quickly overlaid. The method is fast, accurate, robust, and scalable.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_263.pdf
filename: SB2012_263.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_263.pdf

title: AUTOTUNE E+ BUILDING ENERGY MODELS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97e08>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97608>
pages: 270-278
abstract: This paper introduces a novel “Autotune” methodol- ogy under development for calibrating building energy models (BEM). It is aimed at developing an automated BEM tuning methodology that enables models to reproduce measured data such as utility bills, sub-meter, and/or sensor data accurately and robustly by selecting best- match E+ input parameters in a systematic, automated, and repeatable fashion. The approach is applicable to a building retrofit scenario and aims to quantify the trade- offs between tuning accuracy and the minimal amount of “ground truth” data required to calibrate the model. Au- totune will use a suite of machine-learning algorithms de- veloped and run on supercomputers to generate calibra- tion functions. Specifically, the project will begin with a de-tuned model and then perform Monte Carlo simula- tions on the model by perturbing the “uncertain” parame- ters within permitted ranges. Machine learning algorithms will then extract minimal perturbation combinations that result in modeled results that most closely track sensor data. A large database of parametric EnergyPlus (E+) simulations has been made publicly available. Autotune is currently being applied to a heavily instrumented residen- tial building as well as three light commercial buildings in which a “de-tuned” model is autotuned using faux sensor data from the corresponding target E+ model.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_270.pdf
filename: SB2012_270.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_270.pdf

title: THERMAL AND MECHANICAL SYSTEMS DESCRIPTORS FOR SIMPLIFIED ENERGY USE EVALUATION OF CANADIAN HOUSES 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc969c8>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96d08>
pages: 279-286
abstract: For a quick and reliable energy evaluation of houses, one needs simple energy analysis software. A key requirement for simplified inputs is to have default data for house geometry, thermal and equipment characteristics based on vintage, type and region in which the house is located. Using data collected from more than 634,000 homes, statistical representative archetype data sets were developed for 35 climates zones and eight vintage periods. Representative numerical approaches were applied to develop archetype house characteristics. These data libraries are integrated with energy simulation software to assist in defining required defaults for geometry, building envelope and equipment. These defaults then provide guidance for a energy advisor to check against actual house data. Comparative energy analyses showed that the archetype characteristics are useful in quick field surveys.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_279.pdf
filename: SB2012_279.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_279.pdf

title: AN INTERACTIVE WORKBENCH FOR MONITORING , IDENTIFICATION AND CALIBRATION OF BUILDING ENERGY MODELS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc96d48>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96d08>
pages: 287-294
abstract: This paper presents a concept and main capabilities of the Matlab-based Building Energy Modeling (BEM) Workbench developed at Ryerson University (Toronto, Canada). The workbench was designed as an interactive tool intended to facilitate and to provide common media for data processing tasks related to various building energy modeling procedures such as (i) on-site data monitoring, (ii) preparation of input data and analysis of simulation results, (iii) validation, verification and calibration of building energy models and (iv) estimation of building thermal parameters. To illustrate the use of the BEM-Workbench several working scenarios are presented. Known inputs from literature methodologies of building thermal parameter estimation were implemented into the workbench to demonstrate one of its purposes as a hypothesis testing tool. Another scenario was introduced to show how the workbench can be used to analyze a buildings model’s dynamic behavior, a critical step in the model’s calibration procedure. Programmatically, the workbench is configured as a set of Matlab GUI components and functions with capability to further expand its functionality.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_287.pdf
filename: SB2012_287.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_287.pdf

title: ESTIMATION OF THERMAL PARAMETERS OF BUILDINGS THROUGH INVERSE MODELING AND CLUSTERING FOR A PORTFOLIO OF BUILDINGS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97c48>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97608>
pages: 295-305
abstract: Estimating heat transfer parameters of building enve- lope for existing buildings is challenging due to limited data from sensors and meters. In this study, we have de- veloped a method for estimating heat transfer parameters of building envelope through clustering technique with in- verse modeling for portfolio of buildings. Firstly, we de- rived a static heat transfer model from a system of dy- namic equations by integrating the equations for differ- ent time periods. The model links monthly energy us- age with cooling and heating loads, and latent heat loads. Secondly, temporal data from a building was used to es- timate the overall heat transfer parameters. Thirdly, a clustering scheme was developed to segment all buildings in the portfolio into different clusters based on similar- ity criteria. The overall heat transfer parameters are then separated into different heat transfer coefficients for wall, roof and windowusing data from multiple buildings in the same cluster. We describe an application of this method to K-12 school buildings in the New York City.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_295.pdf
filename: SB2012_295.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_295.pdf

title: A FRAMEWORK FOR ESTIMATING THE POTENTIAL ENERGY SAVINGS OF NATURAL VENTILATION RETROFITS FOR CALIFORNIA COMMERCIAL BUILDINGS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97c08>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97e48>
pages: 306-313
abstract: This paper proposes an approach for estimating the potential energy savings of retrofitting existing commercial buildings in California for natural ventilation. 308 baseline commercial building models are developed in EnergyPlus based on a characterization of the existing California commercial building stock. Each baseline model and five retrofit options are simulated in the 16 California Climate Zones using TMY3 weather files and energy savings are calculated. Building weights are developed and applied to expand the estimated energy savings to the statewide level. Based on the findings, recommendations will be made to assist policy makers, building designers and owners in making informed decisions regarding the efficacy of natural ventilation retrofits.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_306.pdf
filename: SB2012_306.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_306.pdf

title: ANNUAL COUPLED ENERGYPLUS AND COMPUTATIONAL FLUID DYNAMICS SIMULATION OF NATURAL VENTILATION 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97d48>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97f88>
pages: 314-321
abstract: Can coupled Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) and Building Energy Simulation (BES) be used to con- duct annual simulation? This paper tries to investigate the feasibility of annual coupled simulation of CFD and BES. Energy modeling approaches have continued to ad- vance to cater for emerging new design concepts towards “greener” solutions that optimize energy consumption in buildings while maintaining thermal comfort as well as healthy environment. Various efforts have been made to improve the fidelity of the thermal simulation in buildings such as to couple CFD with lumped nodal BES model. Research has shown that the coupled simulation improves simulation accuracy. However, due to the nature of CFD simulation, coupled simulation usually takes much longer computation time. For example, the annual simulation of natural ventilation, which has relatively fewer incidences of CFD simulation runs, would take up to 46 days. In ad- dressing the issue, a coupled lumped heat transfer model (EnergyPlus) and CFD model (Fluent) was implemented, and 8 days of simulation was conducted. Delaunay Tri- angulation based interpolation model was built from the 8 days’ results, which can be used to predict the airflow rates for openings for an annual simulation. It is shown that the interpolation model is able to predict 35% of the natural ventilation deployable time annually, when natu- ral ventilation is appropriate in the Philadelphia climate context. The interpolation model reduces the simulation time by 90%
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_314.pdf
filename: SB2012_314.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_314.pdf

title: USING CFD SIMULATIONS TO IMPROVE THEMODELING OFWINDOW DISCHARGE COEFFICIENTS 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97048>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc96f48>
pages: 322-328
abstract: Accurate parameterization of flow through window openings is necessary in order to model passive and mixed-mode ventilation strategies using airflow network models and energy simulation tools. In these tools, lit- tle guidance is typically provided on selecting airflow pa- rameters such as the discharge coefficient for windows. Detailed computationalfluid dynamics (CFD) simulations can provide an inexpensive, flexible method for develop- ing such parameterizations. In this study, the discharge coefficient for pivoted windows is considered, using an- alytical and CFD modeling as well as comparison with previous data. The discharge coefficient parameteriza- tion currently used in EnergyPlus can lead to an under- estimate of flow through pivoted windows by up to fac- tor of 2. This parameterization for the discharge coeffi- cient as a function of window angle and aspect ratio is modified, and Reynolds-averaged numerical simulations are used to validate this new formulation. Analytical and numerical results compare well with measurements from windowmanufacturers.
url: internal-pdf://SB2012_322.pdf
filename: SB2012_322.pdf
galleyURL: https://github.com/muehleisen/IPBSA-USA-Pubs/raw/master/mendeley%20files/2012/SB2012_322.pdf

title: COUPLED ENERGYPLUS AND COMPUTATIONAL FLUID DYNAMICS NATURAL VENTILATION SIMULATION 
first names: <Element firstname at 0x1342bc97f08>
last names: <Element lastname at 0x1342bc97e48>
pages: 329-336
